<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<?asciidoc-toc?><?asciidoc-numbered?><book lang="en">
<title>Big Data Bibliography</title>
<bookinfo>
    <title>Big Data Bibliography</title>
  <edition>1</edition>
  <author>
    <firstname>Editors of Safari Books Online</firstname>
  </author>
  <isbn>9781449316266</isbn>
</bookinfo>
<preface id="_introduction">
<title>Introduction</title>
<simpara>The exponentially decreasing costs of data storage have made the cost of recording and storing data almost free, and certainly convenient for us all to take advantage of. Events previously deemed unworthy of recording are yielding valuable insights for existing businesses and sprouting whole new industries. Recording data and later analyzing it isn’t just for the entrepreneurial spirit, since it does result in some amazing discoveries. In business and government, organizations leveraging data-based decisions are more successful than those relying on decades of trial-and-error. To make these data based decisions, the data needs to be collected, processed and distilled in a manner humans can understand. It is the IT department that is responsible for connecting these data pipes and separating the signal from the noise.</simpara>
<simpara>Those involved in data wrangling would have easier jobs if the processing power of a single machine could keep up with the size of the data they needed to process. The fact is it hasn’t, and over the past decade a new field of big data has emerged. This big data field is focused on reliably processing massive amounts of data. Processing large amounts of data has been done in the past, but what is new this time around is that it’s being done on commodity hardware and open-source software tools.</simpara>
<simpara>We have chosen a selection of the most useful books for data analysis in this bibliography. These start from high level concepts of business intelligence, data analysis and data mining. The list then works its way down to the tools needed for number crunching mathematical toolkits, machine learning, and natural language processing. In order to implement these concepts beyond the “toy” stage, infrastructure tools are covered in Cloud Services and Infrastructure and Amazon Web Services. Finally big data tools that can be deployed in the cloud or locally are covered in the Hadoop, and NoSqL Data Stores section.</simpara>
</preface>
<chapter id="_data_analysis">
<title>Data Analysis</title>
<simpara>This a broad category that serves as an introduction to the process of making data-based decisions.  This category covers basic analysis
using simple tools such as: Excel and SQL.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_data_analysis_with_open_source_tools">
<title>Data Analysis with Open Source Tools</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Philipp K. Janert</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, November 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449389802</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>538 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449389802_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>In this book, Philipp Janert teaches you how to approach data analysis problems and extract all of the information available from your data. Collecting data is relatively easy, but turning raw information into something useful requires that you know how to extract precisely what you need. With this insightful book, intermediate to experienced programmers interested in data analysis will learn techniques for working with data in a business environment. You’ll learn how to look at data to discover what it contains, how to capture those ideas in conceptual models, and how to feed your understanding back into the organization through business plans, metrics dashboards, and other applications. Above all, you’ll learn how to think about the results you want to achieve, rather than rely on tools to think for you.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781449389802?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_head_first_data_analysis">
<title>Head First Data Analysis</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Michael Milton</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, July 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596806224</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>496 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596806224_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Interpreting data is a critical decision-making factor for businesses and organizations. Use this book to learn how to collect and organize data, sort the distractions from the truth, find meaningful patterns, draw conclusions, predict the future, and present your findings to others. Whether you’re a product developer researching the market viability of a new product or service, a marketing manager gauging or predicting the effectiveness of a campaign, a salesperson who needs data to support product presentations, or a lone entrepreneur responsible for all of these data-intensive functions, this book will help you learn how to convert raw data into a vital business tool. Using the latest research in cognitive science and learning theory to craft a multi-sensory learning experience, this book is designed for the way your brain works, not a text-heavy approach that puts you to sleep.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596806224?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_data_analysis_using_sql_and_excel">
<title>Data Analysis Using SQL and Excel</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Gordon S. Linoff</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, October 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470099513</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>744 pages, $45.00 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470099513_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>In this book, one of the leading experts on business data mining shows you how to leverage SQL and Excel to perform sophisticated types of business analysis, without the expense of data mining tools and consultants. Each chapter discusses why and when to perform a particular type of business analysis to obtain a useful business result, with helpful tips and hints, and how to design and perform the analysis using SQL and Excel, including what the results look like in SQL and Excel.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470099513?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_microsoft_excel_2010_data_analysis_and_business_modeling">
<title>Microsoft Excel 2010: Data Analysis and Business Modeling</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Wayne L. Winston</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Microsoft Press, January 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780735656864</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>720 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780735656864_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book will help you master the data analysis and modeling techniques in Excel 2010 that help you transform data into bottom-line results. These materials have been tested while teaching thousands of analysts working for Fortune 500 corporations and government agencies, including the U.S. Army. In this book you’ll learn about statistics, forecasting, optimization models, Monte Carlo simulation, inventory modeling, and the mathematics of waiting in line. You will also learn about some recent developments in business thinking, such as real options, customer value, and mathematical pricing models. You will even learn how to predict U.S. presidential elections, how to set football point spreads, how to determine the probability of winning at craps, and how to determine the probability of a specific team winning an NCAA tournament. These examples are interesting and fun, and they teach you a lot about solving business problems with Excel.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780735656864?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_access_data_analysis_cookbook">
<title>Access Data Analysis Cookbook</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Ken Bluttman; Wayne S. Freeze</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, May 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596101220</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>368 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/0596101228_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book offers practical recipes to solve a variety of common problems that users have with extracting Access data and performing calculations on it. Each recipe includes a discussion on how and why the solution works. Whether you use Access 2007 or an earlier version, this book will teach you new methods to query data, different ways to move data in and out of Access, and how to calculate answers to financial and investment issues. Learn how to apply statistics to summarize business information, how to jump beyond SQL by manipulating data with VBA, how to process dates and times, and even how to reach into the Excel data analysis toolkit. This book is a one-stop-shop for extracting nuggets of valuable information from your database, and anyone with Access experience will benefit from these tips and techniques, including seasoned developers. If you want to use your data, and not just store it, you’ll find this guide indispensable.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596101220?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_practical_data_analysis_and_reporting_with_birt">
<title>Practical Data Analysis and Reporting with BIRT</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By John Ward</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Packt Publishing, February 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781847191090</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>312 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781847191090_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>BIRT, which stands for Business Intelligence and Reporting Tools, is a collection of development tools and technologies used for report development utilizing the BIRT framework. This book focuses on the most visible and familiar product built with the BIRT framework, which is the BIRT Report Designer. The BIRT Report Designer is an Eclipse plug-in that utilizes BIRT technologies to allow users to design reports in the BIRT document format. You can integrate it with your Java/J2EE applications to produce compelling reports. This book is a concise and practical guide aimed at getting the results you want as quickly as possible. It steers you through each point of reporting from setup, to scripting, designing, formatting, and deploying BIRT reports using a common example that runs through the book. This book is for Java developers who want to create rich reports and get started with BIRT to do this.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781847191090?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_jmp_start_statistics_a_guide_to_statistics_and_data_analysis_using_jmp">
<title>JMP Start Statistics: A Guide to Statistics and Data Analysis Using JMP</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By John Sall; Lee Creighton; Ann Lehman</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>SAS Publishing, September 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781599945729</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>628 pages, $59.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781599945729_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is an introduction to analyzing data using JMP statistical discovery software from SAS. A mix of software manual and statistics text, this book provides hands-on tutorials with just the right amount of conceptual and motivational material to illustrate how to use JMP’s intuitive interface for data analysis. Each chapter features concept-specific tutorials, examples, brief reviews of concepts, step-by-step illustrations, and exercises. A few of the techniques in this book are not found in most introductory statistics courses, but are accessible in basic form using JMP. These techniques include logistic regression, correspondence analysis, principal components with biplots, leverage plots, and density estimation. All of these techniques are used in the service of understanding other, more basic methods.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781599945729?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_excel_data_analysis_your_visual_blueprint_for_creating_and_analyzing_data_charts_and_pivottables_3rd_edition">
<title>Excel Data Analysis: Your visual blueprint for creating and analyzing data, charts, and PivotTables, 3rd Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Denise Etheridge</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Visual, July 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470591604</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>368 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470591604_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Crunch and analyze Excel data the way the professionals do with this clean, uncluttered, visual guide to advanced Excel techniques. Using numerous screenshots and easy-to-follow numbered steps, this book clearly shows you how to perform professional-level modeling, charting, data access, data slicing, and other functions. You’ll find super techniques for getting the most out of Excel’s statistical and financial functions, Excel PivotTables and PivotCharts. It includes practical examples, tips, and advice to help you get the most out of Excel’s features and functions. Follow along and earn Excel at the highest levels with this practical guide.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470591604?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_practical_data_analysis_with_jmp">
<title>Practical Data Analysis with JMP</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Robert Carver</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>SAS Publishing, July 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781607644750</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>396 pages, $49.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781607644750_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book provides a powerful interactive and visual approach of JMP, introducing readers to the logic and methods of statistical thinking and data analysis. It includes a myriad of examples and problems that rely on real sets of data, often starting with an important or interesting research question that an investigator has pursued. The chapters are organized around core statistical concepts rather than software commands, menus, or features. And most of the data sets in this book are real and are drawn from those disciplines whose practitioners are the primary users of JMP software.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781607644750?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_visual_six_sigma_making_data_analysis_lean">
<title>Visual Six Sigma: Making Data Analysis Lean</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Ian Cox; Marie A. Gaudard; Philip J. Ramsey; Mia L. Stephens; Leo Wright</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons December 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470506912</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>504 pages, $49.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470506912_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>In the typical business environment of process improvement, you want simple-to-use tools that everyone can use at all levels to rapidly explore and interpret data. This book helps you use your own data to drive incredible improvement within your business. It is divided into three parts: background, case studies, and JMP highlights. Broaden and deepen your application of Six Sigma thinking within your organization with the intuitive and easy to use tools detailed in this book.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470506912?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_categorical_data_analysis_using_the_sas_system_2nd_edition">
<title>Categorical Data Analysis Using The SAS System, 2nd Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>Maura E. Stokes; Charles S. Davis; Gary G. Koch</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>SAS Publishing June 2000</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781580257107</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>648 pages, $67.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781580257107_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Statisticians and researchers will find this book essential with its discussion of categorical data analysis techniques and tips on applying these methods with SAS. Practical examples from a broad range of applications illustrate the use of the FREQ, LOGISTIC, GENMOD, and CATMOD procedures in a variety of analyses. Other procedures discussed include the PHREG and NPAR1WAY procedures. Topics discussed include assessing association in contingency tables and sets of tables, logistic regression and conditional logistic regression, and more. This second edition has been revised for use with SAS 8. New topics include additional exact tests, generalized estimating equations, use of the CLASS statement in the LOGISTIC procedure, exact logistic regression using the LOGISTIC procedure, and comparisons of the use of subject-specific models versus population-averaged models.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781580257107?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_data_mining">
<title>Data Mining</title>
<simpara>This is an introduction to advanced techniques of data analysis.  This section introduces readers into areas where data mining is
currently being used, as well as tools for doing data mining.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_programming_collective_intelligence">
<title>Programming Collective Intelligence</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Toby Segaran</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, August 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596529321</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>368 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596529321_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Want to tap the power behind search rankings, product recommendations, social bookmarking, and online matchmaking? This fascinating book demonstrates how you can build Web 2.0 applications to mine the enormous amount of data created by people on the Internet. With the sophisticated algorithms in this book, you can write smart programs to access interesting datasets from other web sites, collect data from users of your own applications, and analyze and understand the data once you’ve found it. This book takes you into the world of machine learning and statistics, and explains how to draw conclusions about user experience, marketing, personal tastes, and human behavior in general. Each algorithm is described clearly and concisely with code that can immediately be used on your web site, blog, Wiki, or specialized application.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596529321?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_mining_the_social_web">
<title>Mining the Social Web</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Matthew A. Russell</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, February 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449394752</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>360 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449394752_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Popular social networks such as Facebook and Twitter generate a tremendous amount of valuable data on topics and use patterns. This concise and practical book shows you how to harvest and analyze data using social web APIs, Python, and pragmatic storage technologies such as Redis, CouchDB, and NetworkX. Algorithms are designed with robustness and efficiency in mind so that the approaches scale well on an ordinary piece of commodity hardware. This book is highly readable from cover to cover as content progressively grows in complexity, but also lends itself to being read in an ad-hoc fashion. Get a concise and straightforward synopsis of some practical technologies from the semantic web landscape that you can incorporate into your analysis as well.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781449394752?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_algorithms_of_the_intelligent_web">
<title>Algorithms of the Intelligent Web</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Haralambos Marmanis; Dmitry Babenko</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Manning Publications, May 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781933988665</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>368 pages, $44.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781933988665_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is an example-driven blueprint for creating applications that collect, analyze, and act on the massive quantities of data users leave in their wake as they use the web. With it you’ll learn how to build Amazon- and Netflix-style recommendation engines, and learn how the same techniques apply to people matches on social-networking sites. You can even see how click-trace analysis can result in smarter ad rotations. With a plethora of examples and extensive detail, this book shows you how to build Web 2.0 applications that are as smart as your users.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781933988665?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_data_mining_with_microsoft_sql_server_2008">
<title>Data Mining with Microsoft SQL Server 2008</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jamie MacLennan, ZhaoHui Tang and Bogdan Crivat</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, November 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470277744</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>672 pages, $50.00 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470277744_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Understand how to use the new features of Microsoft SQL Server 2008 for data mining by using the tools in this book, which show you how to use the SQL Server Data Mining Toolset with Office 2007 to mine and analyze data. Explore each of the major data mining algorithms, including naive bayes, decision trees, time series, clustering, association rules, and neural networks. Learn more about topics like mining OLAP databases, data mining with SQL Server Integration Services 2008, and using Microsoft data mining to solve business analysis problems. This is the most authoritative book on data mining with SQL Server 2008.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470277744?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_practical_applications_of_data_mining">
<title>Practical Applications of Data Mining</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Sang C. Suh</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Jones &amp; Bartlett Learning, January 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780763785871</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>420 pages, $82.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780763785871_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book emphasizes both theory and the applications of data mining algorithms. Various topics of data mining techniques are identified and described throughout, including clustering, association rules, rough set theory, probability theory, neural networks, classification, and fuzzy logic. Each of these techniques is explored with a theoretical introduction and its effectiveness is demonstrated with various chapter examples. This book will help any database and IT professional understand how to apply data mining techniques to real-world problems.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780763785871?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read in Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_data_mining_for_business_intelligence_concepts_techniques_and_applications_in_microsoft_office_excel_with_xlminer_second_edition">
<title>Data Mining For Business Intelligence: Concepts, Techniques, and Applications in Microsoft Office Excel with XLMiner, Second Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Galit Shmueli; Nitin R. Patel; Peter C. Bruce</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, October 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470526828</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>428 pages, $120 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470526828_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book uses real data and actual cases to illustrate the applicability of data mining (DM) intelligence in the development of successful business models. Featuring complimentary access to XLMiner, the Microsoft Office Excel add-in, this book allows readers to follow along and implement algorithms at their own speed, with a minimal learning curve. In addition, students and practitioners of DM techniques are presented with hands-on, business-oriented applications. An abundant amount of exercises and examples, now doubled in number in the second edition, are provided to motivate learning and understanding. This book helps readers understand the beneficial relationship that can be established between DM and smart business practices, and is an excellent learning tool for creating valuable strategies and making wiser business decisions.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470526828?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_introduction_to_data_mining_using_sas_enterprise_miner">
<title>Introduction to Data Mining: Using SAS Enterprise Miner</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Patricia B. Cerrito</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>SAS Publishing, November 2006</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781590478295</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>488 pages, $89.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781590478295_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is packed with examples from an array of industries, and provides you with excellent starting points and practical guidelines to begin data mining today. The author encourages you to think of data mining as a process of exploration rather than as a collection of tools to investigate data. In that way, you choose the methods that will extract the most information from your data, and, while there are no right answers to investigating data sets, there are many questions that can be asked to produce meaningful results. Each answer then creates a path that helps you drill down to explore the data fully. It is up to you to determine what is of interest and what is important to analyze.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781590478295?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_data_mining_and_knowledge_discovery_technologies">
<title>Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery Technologies</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By David Taniar</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IGI Global, January 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781599049601</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>379 pages, $99.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781599049601_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>As information technology continues to advance in massive increments, the bank of information available from personal, financial, and business electronic transactions and all other electronic documentation and data storage is growing at an exponential rate. With this wealth of information comes the opportunity and necessity to use this information to maintain a competitive advantage and process information effectively in real-world situations. This book presents researchers and practitioners with comprehensive, innovative research on data mining methods, structures, tools, and methods.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781599049601?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_decision_trees_for_business_intelligence_and_data_mining_using_sas_enterprise_miner">
<title>Decision Trees for Business Intelligence and Data Mining: Using SAS Enterprise Miner</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Barry de Ville</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>SAS Publishing, October 2006</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781590475676</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>240 pages, $49.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781590475676_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book illustrates the application and operation of decision trees in business intelligence, data mining, business analytics, prediction, and knowledge discovery. It explains in detail the use of decision trees as a data mining technique and how this technique complements and supplements data mining approaches such as regression, as well as other business intelligence applications that incorporate tabular reports, OLAP, or multidimensional cubes. Examples show how various aspects of decision trees are constructed, how they operate, how to interpret them, and how to use them in a range of predictive and descriptive applications. The examples are drawn from the areas of purchase behavior, risk assessment, and business-to-business marketing. This book also describes the various disciplines that contributed to the development of decision trees and how, even today, decision trees can be used as a form of machine intelligence.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781590475676?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_temporal_and_spatio_temporal_data_mining">
<title>Temporal and Spatio-Temporal Data Mining</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Wynne Hsu; Mong Li Lee; Junmei Wang</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IGI Global, July 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781599043876</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>292 pages, $99.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781599043876_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book examines the problem of mining topological patterns in spatio-temporal databases by imposing the temporal constraints into the process of mining spatial collocation patterns. It presents probable solutions when discovering the spatial sequence patterns by incorporating the spatial information into the sequence of patterns, and introduces two new classes of spatial sequence patterns: flow patterns and generalized spatio-temporal patterns. This innovative book addresses different scenarios when finding complex relationships in spatio-temporal data by modeling them as graphs, giving readers a comprehensive synopsis on two successful partition-based algorithms designed by the authors.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781599043876?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_data_mining_and_medical_knowledge_management_cases_and_applications">
<title>Data Mining and Medical Knowledge Management: Cases and Applications</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Petr Berka; Jan Rauch; Djamel Abdelkader Zighed</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IGI Global, February 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781605662183</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>464 pages, $225 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781605662183_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book presents 20 case studies on applications of various modern data mining methods in several important areas of medicine. It covers classical data mining methods, elaborated approaches related to mining in electroencephalogram and electrocardiogram data, and even methods related to mining in genetic data.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781605662183?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_intelligent_soft_computation_and_evolving_data_mining_integrating_advanced_technologies">
<title>Intelligent Soft Computation and Evolving Data Mining: Integrating Advanced Technologies</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Leon Shyue-Liang Wang; Tzung-Pei Hong</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IGI Global, March 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781615207572</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>516 pages, $180 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781615207572_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book provides a reference to researchers, practitioners, and students in both soft computing and data mining communities, forming a foundation for the development of the field. It integrates contrasting techniques of conventional hard computing and soft computing to exploit the tolerance for imprecision, uncertainty, partial truth, and approximation to achieve tractability, robustness and low-cost solution.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781615207572?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_building_intelligent_net_applications_agents_data_mining_rule_based_systems_and_speech_processing">
<title>Building Intelligent .NET Applications: Agents, Data Mining, Rule-Based Systems, and Speech Processing</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Sara Morgan Rea</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Addison-Wesley Professional, March 2005</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780321246264</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>312 pages, $54.99</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/0321246268_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is an introduction to the world of Artificial Intelligence (AI) for .NET programmers. It is the first book to show professional .NET developers how to incorporate AI into their daily programming. In this accessible guide, developers will learn how to enhance both new and existing .NET applications with intelligent agents, data mining, rule-based systems, and speech processing. The author explores four of the most popular AI technologies by building real-world sample applications that readers can use as the basis for their own applications. With the help of this book, developers will learn the basic technologies of AI needed to create practical, time-saving enterprise applications.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780321246264?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_data_mining_applications_for_empowering_knowledge_societies">
<title>Data Mining Applications for Empowering Knowledge Societies</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Hakikur Rahman</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IGI Global, July 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781599046570</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>356 pages, $180 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781599046570_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book presents an overview of the main issues of data mining, including its classification, regression, clustering, and ethical issues. This comprehensive book also provides readers with knowledge enhancing processes as well as a wide spectrum of data mining applications.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781599046570?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_social_and_political_implications_of_data_mining_knowledge_management_in_e_government">
<title>Social and Political Implications of Data Mining: Knowledge Management in E-Government</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Hakikur Rahman</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IGI Global, February 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781605662305</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>378 pages, $195 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781605662305_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book focuses on the data mining and knowledge management implications that lie within online government. This significant reference book contains cases for the improvement of governance systems, the enhancement of security techniques, and the empowerment of citizens and societies. It covers the data mining and knowledge management implications that lie within online government.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781605662305?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_data_mining_patterns_new_methods_and_applications">
<title>Data Mining Patterns: New Methods and Applications</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Pascal Poncelet; Florent Masseglia; Maguelonne Teisseire</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IGI Global, August 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781599041629</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>323 pages, $180 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781599041629_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book provides an overall view of the solutions for mining, and also explores new kinds of patterns. This book offers theoretical frameworks and presents challenges and their possible solutions concerning pattern extractions, emphasizing both research techniques and real-world applications. This book portrays research applications in data models, techniques and methodologies for mining patterns, multi-relational and multidimensional pattern mining, fuzzy data mining, data streaming, incremental mining, and many other topics.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781599041629?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_data_mining_with_ontologies_implementations_findings_and_frameworks">
<title>Data Mining with Ontologies: Implementations, Findings, and Frameworks</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Hector Oscar Nigro; Sandra Elizabeth Gonzalez Cisaro; Daniel Hugo Xodo</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IGI Global, July 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781599046181</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>311 pages, $180 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781599046181_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>One of the most important and challenging problems in data mining is the definition of prior knowledge either from the process or the domain. Prior knowledge is helpful for selecting suitable data and mining techniques, pruning the space of hypothesis, representing the output in a comprehensible way, and improving the overall method. This book provides a comprehensive set of methodologies and tools for the development of ontological foundations for data mining in diverse domains ranging from biomedicine to marketing. Forming a benchmark reference for future efforts to enhance capabilities in ontology utilization and design, this book is an invaluable addition to libraries worldwide.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781599046181?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_data_mining_with_microsoft_sql_server_2000_technical_reference">
<title>Data Mining with Microsoft SQL Server 2000: Technical Reference</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Claude Seidman</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Microsoft Press, May 2001</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780735650916</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>384 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780735650916_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book examines the SQL Server 2000 Analysis Services architecture and shows how data mining fits into its complete suite of information-extraction technologies. It also demonstrates how to find nuggets of useful information with SQL Server. It covers what data mining is and isn’t, plus important principles and definitions behind data-mining methodologies, including the role of data-mining models, statistics, and algorithms.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780735650916?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read in Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_business_intelligence">
<title>Business Intelligence</title>
<simpara>Business intelligence is the application of data analysis to business data.  The titles in this section demonstrate some tools useful for
business intelligence, as well as introduce the reader to the subject. These tools cover the back end through the front end.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_microsoft_sql_server_2008_business_intelligence_development_and_maintenance_mcts_self_paced_training_kit_exam_70_448">
<title>Microsoft SQL Server 2008-Business Intelligence Development and Maintenance: MCTS Self-Paced Training Kit (Exam 70-448)</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Erik Veerman; Teo Lachev; Dejan Sarka</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Microsoft Press, April 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780735626362</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>688 pages, $55.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780735626362_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Ace your preparation for the skills measured by MCTS Exam 70-448 and on the job. This official Microsoft study guide is designed to help you make the most of your study time. Maximize your performance on the exam by learning to: Create SSIS packages; troubleshoot data flow and control flow; configure, debug, and deploy SSIS solutions, and more. You can work through hundreds of questions using multiple testing modes to meet your specific learning needs. You get detailed explanations for right and wrong answers including a customized learning path that describes how and where to focus your studies. There are 200 practice and review questions and this comes with a 180-day trial of SQL Server 2008 Enterprise Edition.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780735626362?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_the_microsoft_data_warehouse_toolkit_with_sql_server_2008_r2_and_the_microsoft_business_intelligence_toolset_second_edition">
<title>The Microsoft Data Warehouse Toolkit: With SQL Server 2008 R2 and the Microsoft Business Intelligence Toolset, Second Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Joy Mundy; Warren Thornthwaite; Ralph Kimball</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470640388</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>696 pages, $50.00 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470640388_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>In this new edition, the authors explain how SQL Server 2008 R2 provides a collection of powerful new tools that extend the power of its BI toolset to Excel and SharePoint users. They also show you how to use SQL Server to build a successful data warehouse that supports the business intelligence requirements that are common to most organizations. Covering the complete suite of data warehousing and BI tools that are part of SQL Server 2008 R2, as well as Microsoft Office, the authors walk you through a full project lifecycle, including design, development, deployment and maintenance. This book features more than 50 percent new and revised material that covers the rich new feature set of the SQL Server 2008 R2 release, as well as the Office 2010 release</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470640388?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_smart_business_intelligence_solutions_with_microsoft_sql_server_2008">
<title>Smart Business Intelligence Solutions with Microsoft SQL Server 2008</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Lynn Langit; Kevin S. Goff; Davide Mauri; Sahil Malik; John Welch</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Microsoft Press, February 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780735625808</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>800 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780735625808_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Get the end-to-end instruction you need to design, develop, and deploy more effective data integration, reporting, and analysis solutions using SQL Server 2008. With real-world examples and insights from an expert team, you will master the concepts, tools, and techniques for building solutions that deliver intelligence and business value exactly where users want it. Details covered in this book include: managing the development life cycle and building a BI team,  writing queries that rank, sort, and drill down on sales data, and using MDX and DMX Query Designers to build reports based on OLAP cubes and data mining models. The book also covers how to create and implement custom objects using .NET code View reports in Microsoft Office Excel and Office SharePoint Server.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780735625808?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_microsoft_sharepoint_2010_business_intelligence_unleashed">
<title>Microsoft SharePoint 2010 Business Intelligence Unleashed</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Steven Mann; Chuck Rivel; Ray Barley; Jim Pletscher; Aneel Ismaily</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Sams, May 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780132660099</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>352 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780132660099_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This is a complete guide to both SharePoint 2010 and BI. This book reflects the unsurpassed real-world experience of five expert consultants at RDA, a Microsoft Gold Partner specializing in delivering advanced BI solutions with SharePoint. The authors offer practical, how-to guidance for every key task involved in building, configuring, and deploying BI solutions within a SharePoint environment, delivering crucial information that can’t be found in any other book. They bridge the gap between SharePoint 2010 and SQL Server 2008, carefully guiding technical professionals on utilizing BI data stored in SQL Server databases. Both a hands-on tutorial and a thorough reference, SharePoint 2010 BI Unleashed will be an indispensable resource for every BI developer, implementer, manager, or integrator working with Microsoft technologies.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780132660099?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_agile_analytics_a_value_driven_approach_to_business_intelligence_and_data_warehousing">
<title>Agile Analytics: A Value-Driven Approach to Business Intelligence and Data Warehousing</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Ken W. Collier</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Addison-Wesley Professional, July 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780321669575</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>368 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780321669575_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Using Agile methods, you can bring far greater innovation, value, and quality to any data warehouse, business intelligence, or analytics project. However, conventional Agile methodologies must be carefully adapted to address the unique characteristics of DW/BI projects. In this book, Agile pioneer Ken Collier introduces platform-agnostic Agile solutions for integrating infrastructures consisting of diverse operational, legacy, and specialty systems that mix commercial and custom code. Using working examples, he shows how to manage analytics development teams with widely diverse skill sets, and how to support enormous and fast-growing data volumes. Collier brings together proven solutions you can apply right now—whether you’re an IT decision-maker, data warehouse professional, DBA, business intelligence specialist, or database developer. With his help, you can mitigate project risk, improve business alignment, achieve better results, and have fun along the way.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780321669575?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_the_kimball_group_reader_relentlessly_practical_tools_for_data_warehousing_and_business_intelligence">
<title>The Kimball Group Reader: Relentlessly Practical Tools for Data Warehousing and Business Intelligence</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Ralph Kimball; Margy Ross; Warren Thornthwaite; Joy Mundy; Bob Becker</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, February 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470563106</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>744 pages, $45 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470563106_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Recognized and respected throughout the world as the most influential leaders in the data warehousing industry, Ralph Kimball and the Kimball Group have written articles covering more than 250 topics that define the field of data warehousing. For the first time, the Kimball Group’s incomparable advice, design tips, and best practices have been gathered in this remarkable collection of articles, which spans a decade of data warehousing innovation. Each group of articles is introduced with original commentaries that explain their role in the overall lifecycle methodology developed by the Kimball Group. These practical, hands-on articles are fully updated to reflect current practices and terminology and cover the complete lifecycle—including project planning, requirements gathering, dimensional modeling, ETL, and business intelligence and analytics.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470563106?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_knight_8217_s_microsoft_business_intelligence_24_hour_trainer_leveraging_microsoft_sql_server_integration_analysis_and_reporting_services_with_excel_and_sharepoint">
<title>Knight’s Microsoft Business Intelligence 24-Hour Trainer: Leveraging Microsoft SQL Server Integration, Analysis, and Reporting Services with Excel and SharePoint</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Brian Knight; Devin Knight; Adam Jorgensen; Patrick LeBlanc; Mike Davis</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Wrox, September 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470889633</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>432 pages, $44.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470889633_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>If you are just starting to get a handle on Microsoft Business Intelligence (BI) tools, this book and accompanying video provides you with the just the right amount of information to perform basic business analysis and reporting. You’ll explore the components and related tools that comprise the Microsoft BI toolset as well as the new BI features of Office 2010. After a basic primer on BI and data modeling, the expert team of authors provides you with step-by-step lessons in the book and videos on the accompanying Video on how to use SQL Server Integration Services, SQL Server Analysis Services, SQL Server Reporting Services, Excel BI (including PowerPivot), and SharePoint.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470889633?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_pentaho_solutions_business_intelligence_and_data_warehousing_with_pentaho_and_mysql">
<title>Pentaho Solutions: Business Intelligence and Data Warehousing with Pentaho and MySQL</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Roland Bouman, Jos van Dongen</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, August 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470484326</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>648 pages, $50 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470484326_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Open-source Pentaho provides business intelligence (BI) and data warehousing solutions at a fraction of the cost of proprietary solutions. Now you can take advantage of Pentaho for your business needs with this practical guide written by two major participants in the Pentaho community. The book covers all of the components of the Pentaho BI Suite. You’ll learn to install, use, and maintain Pentaho-and find plenty of background discussion that will bring you thoroughly up to speed on BI and Pentaho concepts.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470484326?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_ibm_cognos_business_intelligence_v10_1_handbook">
<title>IBM Cognos Business Intelligence V10.1 Handbook</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Dean Browne; Brecht Desmeijter; Rodrigo Frealdo Dumont; Armin Kamal; John Leahy; Scott Masson; Ksenija Rusak; Shinsuke Yamamoto; Martin Keen</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IBM Redbooks, October 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780738434810</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>572 pages, $68.75 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/0738434817_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book helps you to meet strategic objectives using IBM Cognos Business Intelligence V10.1 software. This IBM Redbooks publication aids you in understanding core features of IBM Cognos BI V10.1, while providing examples with practical scenarios.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780738434810?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_business_intelligence_for_dummies">
<title>Business Intelligence For Dummies</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Swain Scheps</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>For Dummies, January 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470127230</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>384 pages, $24.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470127230_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>So you’ve already figured out that Business Intelligence can be pretty valuable in making the right decisions about your business. But you’ve heard at least a dozen definitions of what it is, and heard of at least that many BI tools. This book makes BI understandable! It takes you step by step through the technologies and the alphabet soup, so you can choose the right technology and implement a successful BI environment. You’ll see how the applications and technologies work together to access, analyze, and present data that you can use to make better decisions about your products, customers and competitors. Whether you’re the business owner or the person charged with developing and implementing a BI strategy, checking out Business Intelligence For Dummies is a good business decision.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470127230?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_pro_sharepoint_2010_business_intelligence_solutions">
<title>Pro SharePoint 2010 Business Intelligence Solutions</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Sahil Malik; Srini Sistla; Steve Wright</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Apress, December 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781430232858</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>430 pages, $59.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781430232858_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Business Intelligence (BI) software is everywhere. It is the code and tools that allow you to view different components of a business using a single visual platform, making comprehending mountains of data easier. With SharePoint 2010, Microsoft has married one of the most-used team collaboration tools with its business intelligence products, including PerformancePoint Services and Excel Services. Now, users of SharePoint can have a single place to get a view of their business, its organization and processes, and its financial performance. Constructing this type of portal is a process unique to each business. This book takes you through the different tools, services, and frameworks available for building a BI portal atop SharePoint 2010. With comprehensive coverage of Visio Services, PerformancePoint, Excel Services, and a practical look at building scorecards, dashboards, and other reporting solutions, this book answers the fundamental questions about why and how BI can work for your business.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781430232858?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_silverlight_4_business_intelligence_software">
<title>Silverlight 4 Business Intelligence Software</title>
<simpara><emphasis>by Bart Czernicki</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Apress, September 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781430230601</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>575 pages, $59.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781430230601_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Rich Internet Application (RIA) technologies such as Microsoft Silverlight can be used to transform traditional user-interfaces filled with boring data into fully interactive analytical applications that quickly deliver insight from large data sets. Furthermore, RIA applications now include 3D spatial-design capabilities that move beyond a simple list or grid and allow for interesting layouts of aggregated data. BI 2.0 implemented via an RIA technology can truly bring out the power of BI and deliver it to an average user on the Web. This book provides developers, designers, and architects with a solid foundation in BI design and architecture concepts for Microsoft Silverlight. It covers key BI design concepts and how they can be applied without an existing BI infrastructure.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781430230601?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_business_intelligence_2">
<title>Business Intelligence</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Elizabeth Vitt; Michael Luckevich; Stacia Misner</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Microsoft Press, December 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780735626607</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>220 pages, $24.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780735626607_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book helps you understand what business intelligence is, how it works, where it’s used, and why and when to use it. This insightful book illustrates how organizations can make better, faster decisions about their customers, partners, and operations by turning mountains of data into valuable business information that’s always at the fingertips of decision makers. You’ll learn what’s involved in using business intelligence to bring together information, people, and technology to create successful business strategies, and how to execute those strategies with confidence.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780735626607?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_powerpivot_for_business_intelligence_using_excel_and_sharepoint">
<title>PowerPivot for Business Intelligence Using Excel and SharePoint</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Barry Ralston</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Apress, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781430233800</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>304 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781430233800_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>PowerPivot comprises a set of technologies for easy access to data mining and business intelligence analysis from Microsoft Excel and SharePoint. Power users and developers alike can create sophisticated, online analytic processing (OLAP) solutions using PowerPivot for Excel, and then share those solutions with other users via PowerPivot for SharePoint. Data can be pulled in from any of the leading database platforms, as well as from spreadsheets and flat files. This book is your key to mastering PowerPivot. The book takes a scenario-based approach to show you how to collect data, to mine that data through insightful analysis, and to draw conclusions that drive business performance. Each chapter in the book is focused on a specific challenge that you’ll encounter when using PowerPivot.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781430233800?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_oracle_business_intelligence_create_reports_amp_interactive_dashboards">
<title>Oracle Business Intelligence: Create Reports &amp; Interactive Dashboards</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Sideris Courseware Corp.</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Sideris Courseware Corp., November 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 01320110029SI</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>480 pages, $120 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/01320110029SI_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Oracle Business Intelligence (BI), formerly known as Siebel Business Analytics, empowers business users with sophisticated data analytic capabilities without any knowledge of database structures or the SQL database language. This training course will guide students through all of the features available from the product to allow you to build sophisticated database requests and to format resulting answers.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/01320110029SI?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_business_intelligence_roadmap_the_complete_project_lifecycle_for_decision_support_applications">
<title>Business Intelligence Roadmap: The Complete Project Lifecycle for Decision-Support Applications</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Larissa T. Moss; Shaku Atre</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Addison-Wesley Professional, February 2003</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780201784206</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>576 pages, $64.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/0201784203_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is a visual guide to developing an effective business intelligence (BI) decision-support application. This book outlines a methodology that takes into account the complexity of developing applications in an integrated BI environment. You are walked through every step of the process—from strategic planning to the selection of new technologies and the evaluation of application releases. The book also serves as a single-source guide to the best practices of BI projects. The authors crystallize their many years of experience in a list of dos, don’ts, tips, and rules of thumb. Both the book and the methodology it describes are designed to adapt to the specific needs of individual stakeholders and organizations. It is a clear and comprehensive guide to negotiating the complexities inherent in the development of valuable business intelligence decision-support applications.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780201784206?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_oracle_business_intelligence_the_condensed_guide_to_analysis_and_reporting">
<title>Oracle Business Intelligence: The Condensed Guide to Analysis and Reporting</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Yuli Vasilev</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Packt Publishing, October 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781849681186</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>184 pages, $35.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781849681186_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>With this book you can quickly learn how to put the power of the Oracle Business Intelligence solution to work for you. The examples in this introductory guide will make you immediately familiar with tools included in the Oracle Business Intelligence package. This book will teach you how to find answers to common business questions and make informed business decisions, and it will help you use the Oracle Business Intelligence SE platform and prepare a database for analysis. You will also learn how to build, deploy and execute reports using Oracle Reports, and integrate data from different data sources with warehousing, employing Oracle Warehouse Builder software. Covering advanced Oracle Business Intelligence features, this book will teach you how to pivot data, drill it up and down, as well as display it visually in graphs.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781849681186?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_the_new_era_of_enterprise_business_intelligence_using_analytics_to_achieve_a_global_competitive_advantage">
<title>The New Era of Enterprise Business Intelligence: Using Analytics to Achieve a Global Competitive Advantage</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Mike Biere</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IBM Press, August 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780132100588</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>320 pages, $44.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780132100588_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>In this book, top BI expert Mike Biere presents a complete blueprint for creating winning BI strategies and infrastructure, systematically maximizing the value of information throughout the enterprise. This product-independent guide brings together start-to-finish guidance and practical checklists for every senior IT executive, planner, strategist, implementer, and the actual business users themselves. Drawing on thousands of hours working with enterprise customers, Biere helps decision-makers choose from today’s unprecedented spectrum of options, including the latest BI platform suites and appliances. He offers practical, “in-the-trenches” insights on a wide spectrum of planning and implementation issues, from segmenting and supporting users to working with unstructured data.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780132100588?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_mathematical_toolkits_r_matlab_mathematica">
<title>Mathematical Toolkits: R, Matlab, Mathematica</title>
<simpara>A number of mathematical software packages are introduced in this section.  These tools kits allow for rapid prototyping of advanced
data analysis methods.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_r_in_a_nutshell">
<title>R in a Nutshell</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Joseph Adler</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, January 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596801700</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>640 pages,  $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449377502_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>R is one of the best tools available for data visualization and statistical computing, and this book is simply the best way to learn this open source language and environment. Practical and easy to read, it demonstrates why R is increasingly popular for analyzing moderate-to-large data sets. Most books available on R are stiff and academic, but this book offers a readable overview of the language, and contains a reference for the most commonly used features.You will learn the basics of the R language, analyze statistics in R, and take advantage of R’s graphical capabilities. With the helpf of this book, scientists, researchers, and students can perform complicated statistical analysis in minutes that would take hours with Excel.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/programming/r/9781449377502?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_r_cookbook">
<title>R Cookbook</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Paul Teetor</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596809157</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>436 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596809287_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>R is a powerful and popular tool for statistics, graphics, and statistical programming.It is a free, open source system whose implementation is the collective accomplishment of many intelligent, hard-working people. But R can be frustrating. It’s not obvious how to accomplish many tasks, even simple ones. This book is full of how-to recipes that solve specific problems. It starts with basic tasks before moving on to input and output, general statistics, graphics, and linear regression. If you are a beginner, this book will get you started faster. If you are an intermediate user, this book is useful for expanding your horizons and jogging your memory. This book will help you be productive with R immediately.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/programming/r/9780596809287?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_matlab_a_practical_introduction_to_programming_and_problem_solving">
<title>MATLAB: A Practical Introduction to Programming and Problem Solving</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Stormy Attaway</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Butterworth-Heinemann, February 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780750687621</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>471 pages, $44.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780750687621_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Assuming no knowledge of programming, this book presents both programming concepts and MATLAB’s built-in functions, providing a perfect platform for exploiting MATLAB’s extensive capabilities for tackling engineering problems. It starts with programming concepts such as variables, assignments, input/output, and selection statements, moves onto loops and then solves problems using both the <emphasis>programming concept</emphasis> and the <emphasis>power of MATLAB</emphasis> side-by-side. In-depth coverage is given to input/output, a topic that is fundamental to many engineering applications.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780750687621?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_mathematica_navigator_mathematics_statistics_and_graphics_third_edition">
<title>Mathematica Navigator: Mathematics, Statistics, and Graphics, Third Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Heikki Ruskeepaa</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Academic Press, March 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780123741646</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>1132 pages, $69.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780123741646_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is a general introduction to the most recent versions of Mathematica, the symbolic computation software from Wolfram. The book emphasizes graphics, methods of applied mathematics and statistics, and programming. This book can be used both as a tutorial and as a handbook. While no previous experience with Mathematica is required, most chapters also include advanced material, so that the book will be a valuable resource for both beginners and experienced users.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780123741646?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_essential_matlab_for_engineers_and_scientists_fourth_edition">
<title>Essential MATLAB for Engineers and Scientists Fourth Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Brian Hahn; Dan Valentine</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Academic Press, October 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780123748836</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>407 pages, $49.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780123748836_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book presents MATLAB both as a mathematical tool and as a programming language, giving a concise and easy to master introduction to its potential and power. The fundamentals of MATLAB are illustrated throughout with many examples from a wide range of familiar scientific and engineering areas, as well as from everyday life. The new edition has been updated to include coverage of Symbolic Math and SIMULINK. It also adds new examples and applications, and uses the most recent release of Matlab.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780123748836?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_mathematica_cookbook">
<title>Mathematica Cookbook</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Sal Mangano</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, May 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596520991</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>832 pages, $64.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449382001_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book helps you master Mathematica’s core principles by walking you through real-world problems. Ideal for browsing, this book includes recipes for working with numerics, data structures, algebraic equations, calculus, and statistics. You’ll also venture into exotic territory with recipes for data visualization using 2D and 3D graphic tools, image processing, and music. Although Mathematica 7 is a highly advanced computational platform, the recipes in this book make it accessible to everyone — whether you’re working on high school algebra, simple graphs, PhD-level computation, financial analysis, or advanced engineering models.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596520991?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_statistical_analysis_with_r">
<title>Statistical Analysis with R</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By John M. Quick</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Packt Publishing, October 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781849512084</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>300 pages, $40.49 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781849512084_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Without any prior experience in programming or statistical software, this book will help you quickly become a knowledgeable user of R. This book will take you on a journey as the strategist for an ancient Chinese kingdom. Along the way, you will learn how to use R to arrive at practical solutions and how to effectively communicate your results. Ultimately, the fate of the kingdom depends upon your ability to make informed, data-driven decisions with R.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781849512084?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_machine_learning_and_natural_language_processing">
<title>Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing</title>
<simpara>This section covers more advanced methods of data analysis including extracting useful data from unstructured human language.  Tools in
this section further show how to use these advance methods on big data.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_hilary_mason_an_introduction_to_machine_learning_with_web_data">
<title>Hilary Mason: An Introduction to Machine Learning with Web Data</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Hilary Mason</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, May 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449309510</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>2 hours 43 minutes, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449309510_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Once you’ve accumulated a pile of data through your web application, what do you do with it? This insightful video course shows you how to solve data analysis problems using basic machine learning techniques and frameworks. You’ll follow several examples through the entire process—from obtaining, cleaning, and exploring data to building a model and interpreting the results.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449309510?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_handbook_of_research_on_machine_learning_applications_and_trends">
<title>Handbook of Research on Machine Learning Applications and Trends</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Emilio Soria Olivas; José David Martín Guerrero; Marcelino Martinez-Sober; Jose Rafael Magdalena-Benedito</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IGI Global, August 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781605667669</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>735 pages, $495.00 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781605667669_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>The machine learning approach provides a useful tool when the amount of data is very large and a model is not available to explain the generation and relation of the data set. This book provides practical applications for solving problems and applying various techniques in automatic data extraction and setting. It fills the gap between theory and practice, providing a strong reference for academicians, researchers, and practitioners.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781605667669?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_real_world_applications_panel_machine_learning_and_decision_support">
<title>Real World Applications Panel: Machine Learning and Decision Support</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jonathan Seidman; Robert Lancaster; Alasdair Allan; Alon Halevy</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449306014</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>41 minutes, $9.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449306014_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Can machines help us make better decisions? In this video, real-world practitioners from the travel, finance, and the energy industry give us an inside look at how they’re applying machine learning to their industries, optimizing the use of resources and helping with decision support.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449306014?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_scaling_data_analysis_with_apache_mahout">
<title>Scaling Data Analysis with Apache Mahout</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Isabel Drost</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449306137</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>38 minutes, $9.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449306137_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>With growing amounts of digital data at the fingertips of software developers, the need for a scalable, easy to use framework is tremendous. This video introduces Apache Mahout—a project with the goal of implementing scalable machine learning algorithms for the masses.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449306137?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_natural_language_processing_with_python">
<title>Natural Language Processing with Python</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Steven Bird; Ewan Klein; Edward Loper</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, June 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596803346</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>512 pages, $44.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596803346_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book offers an introduction to natural language processing, the field that supports a variety of language technologies, from predictive text and email filtering to automatic summarization and translation. With it, you’ll learn how to write Python programs that work with large collections of unstructured text. You’ll access richly annotated datasets using a comprehensive range of linguistic data structures, and you’ll understand the main algorithms for analyzing the content and structure of written communication. This book will help you gain practical skills in natural language processing using the Python programming language and the Natural Language Toolkit (NLTK) open source library. If you’re interested in developing web applications, analyzing multilingual news sources, or documenting endangered languages — or if you’re simply curious to have a programmer’s perspective on how human language works — you’ll find this book both fascinating and immensely useful.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596803346?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_online_sentiment_machine_learning_and_prediction">
<title>Online Sentiment, Machine Learning, and Prediction</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Ben Gimpert; Josh Merchant; Ryan Strynatka; Margaret Francis</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449306205</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>34 minutes, $9.99</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449306205_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Today’s web analyst has moved far beyond funnels and visitors. Automated systems decide who gets what content, and language parsing tries to distill sentiment from millions of online interactions. This video looks at where web analytics is headed, and how new algorithms and approaches are yielding fresh insights into online commerce.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449306205?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_analytics">
<title>Analytics</title>
<simpara>Analytics is the collection and analysis of data that is used to help in decision making. Explore the big data books in this section to get a grasp on making smart business decisions.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_web_analytics_2_0_the_art_of_online_accountability_and_science_of_customer_centricity">
<title>Web Analytics 2.0: The Art of Online Accountability and Science of Customer Centricity</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Avinash Kaushik</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Sybex, October 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470529393</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>503 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470529393_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Web Analytics 2.0 presents a new framework that will permanently change how you think about analytics. It provides specific recommendations for creating an actionable strategy, applying analytical techniques correctly, solving challenges such as measuring social media and multichannel campaigns, achieving optimal success by leveraging experimentation, and employing tactics for truly listening to your customers. The book will help your organization become more data driven while you become a super analysis ninja!</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470529393?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_google_analytics">
<title>Google Analytics</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Justin Cutroni</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, September 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449394608</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>224 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449394608_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Take advantage of Google Analytics’ powerful and free tools to understand exactly how users behave when they visit your website or use your web application. This book shows you how to probe general traffic, marketing, and ecommerce information with these tools, and teaches you how to supplement them with add-ons and external tools when you want to dig even deeper. You’ll also learn how to create custom reports to analyze specific issues. Remember, Google Analytics analyzes business data, which means each business will configure it differently. You need to understand what’s important for your business, and this book will help you.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781449394608?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_advanced_web_metrics_with_google_analytics_second_edition">
<title>Advanced Web Metrics with Google Analytics, Second Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Brian Clifton</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Sybex, March 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470562314</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>527 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470562314_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Packed with insider tips and tricks, this how-to guide is fully revised to cover the latest version of Google Analytics and shows you how to implement proven Web analytics methods and concepts. It is the perfect book for marketers, vendors, consultants, and Webmasters who want to learn the installation, configuration, tracking techniques, and best practices of Google Analytics. This book is a detailed usage guide written by one of the software’s original creators, and is valuable for both novice and experienced users of Google Analytics.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470562314?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_sams_teach_yourself_google_analytics_in_10_minutes">
<title>Sams Teach Yourself Google Analytics in 10 Minutes</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Michael Miller</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Sams, July 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780132120807</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>240 pages, $14.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780132120807_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book provides you with straightforward, practical answers when you need fast results. By working through its 10-minute lessons, you’ll learn everything you need to use Google Analytics to accurately measure your website’s performance–and improve it! This includes learning how to track visitors from search engines, pay-per-click advertising, and email. It will also help you identify your best and worst content, fix poorly performing pages, and improve your site by tracking error pages and broken links. You’ll even learn how to choose the right reports and data, understand them, and act on what you learn.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780132120807?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_search_analytics_for_your_site_conversations_with_your_customers">
<title>Search Analytics for Your Site: Conversations with Your Customers</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Louis Rosenfeld</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Rosenfeld Media, July 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781457102523</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>224 pages, $22 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781457102523_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book shows you how to use search analytics to listen to and understand your customers’ needs, and improve your content, navigation and search performance to meet those needs. If you’re new to this topic read the first two chapters, but if you are ready to jump right in, the second section is full of tools and approaches to help you get the most out of analyzing your query data. The book moves on to help you gain new insights from your data and use the data to measure how well your site is performing against the goals you’ve already determined for it. You will also learn ways to improve your search system’s performance, as well as your site’s navigation, metadata, and content. You can start trying—and benefiting from—many of these tips right away.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781457102523?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_business_intelligence_making_decisions_through_data_analytics">
<title>Business Intelligence: Making Decisions Through Data Analytics</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jerzy Surma</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Business Expert Press, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781606491850</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>150 pages, $27 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781606491850_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Focusing on practical business issues, this text demonstrates how to apply data warehousing and data analytics to support business decision making. This book progresses through a logical sequence, starting with data model infrastructure, then data preparation, followed by data analysis, integration, knowledge discovery, and finally the actual use of discovered knowledge. All of the examples are based upon the most recent achievements in business intelligence. This book covers a methodology that takes into account the complexity of developing applications in an integrated business intelligence environment, and is written for managers, business consultants, and students in business administration.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781606491850?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_the_new_era_of_enterprise_business_intelligence_using_analytics_to_achieve_a_global_competitive_advantage_2">
<title>The New Era of Enterprise Business Intelligence: Using Analytics to Achieve a Global Competitive Advantage</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Mike Biere</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IBM Press, August 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780132100588</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>320 pages, $44.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780132100588_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>The typical enterprise recognizes the immense potential of business intelligence (BI) and its impact upon many facets within the organization, but it’s not easy to transform BI’s potential into real business value. In this book, top BI expert Mike Biere presents a complete blueprint for creating winning BI strategies to help maximize the value of information throughout the enterprise. This product-independent guide brings together start-to-finish guidance and practical checklists for every senior IT executive, planner, strategist, implementer, and the actual business users themselves. Drawing on thousands of hours working with enterprise customers, Biere helps decision-makers choose from today’s unprecedented spectrum of options, including the latest BI platform suites and appliances. He offers practical, “in-the-trenches” insights on a wide spectrum of planning and implementation issues, from segmenting and supporting users to working with unstructured data.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780132100588?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_performance_marketing_with_google_analytics_practical_strategies_for_maximizing_online_roi">
<title>Performance Marketing with Google Analytics: Practical Strategies for Maximizing Online ROI</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Sebastian Tonkin; Caleb Whitmore; Justin Cutroni</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, April 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470578315</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>504 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470578315_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>An unparalleled author trio shares valuable advice for using Google Analytics to achieve your business goals in this book. Google Analytics is a free tool used by millions of Web site owners across the globe to track how visitors interact with their Web sites, where they arrive from, and which visitors drive the most revenue and sales leads. This book offers clear explanations of practical applications drawn from the real world. It features in-depth examples and case studies on how to increase revenue from search advertising, how to optimize an existing website, and how to prioritize channels and campaigns. This book demonstrates how you can best use Google Analytics to achieve your business objectives.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470578315?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_google_analytics_third_edition">
<title>Google Analytics Third Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jerri L. Ledford; Joe Teixeira; Mary E. Tyler</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, December 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470531280</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>432 pages, $34.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470531280_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>With great new features including advanced customization and segmentation capabilities, Google Analytics supplies information about your site visitors that helps you ramp up the value of your site. Like its two previous editions, this guide shows you what’s new in Google Analytics, how to get the most from the program, and what to do with what you learn. It explores new features such as AdSense integration, cost data settings, motion charts, custom reports, and event tracking, drilling down with advanced techniques, tips, and hacks.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470531280?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_web_analytics_an_hour_a_day">
<title>Web Analytics: An Hour a Day</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Avinash Kaushik</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Sybex, June 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470130650</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>480 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470130650_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Written by an in-the-trenches practitioner, this step-by-step guide shows you how to implement a successful Web analytics strategy. Web analytics expert Avinash Kaushik, in his thought-provoking style, debunks leading myths and leads you on a path to gaining actionable insights from your analytics efforts. Discover how to move beyond clickstream analysis, why qualitative data should be your focus, and more insights and techniques that will help you develop a customer-centric mindset without sacrificing your company’s bottom line.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470130650?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_tapping_into_unstructured_data_integrating_unstructured_data_and_textual_analytics_into_business_intelligence">
<title>Tapping into Unstructured Data: Integrating Unstructured Data and Textual Analytics into Business Intelligence</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By William H. Inmon; Anthony Nesavich</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Prentice Hall, December 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780137136889</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>264 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780137136889_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>A wealth of invaluable information exists in unstructured textual form, but organizations have found it difficult or impossible to access and utilize it. This is changing rapidly: new approaches finally make it possible to glean useful knowledge from virtually any collection of unstructured data. William H. Inmon—the father of data warehousing—and Anthony Nesavich introduce the next data revolution: unstructured data management. This book covers all you need to know to make unstructured data work for your organization. You’ll learn how to bring it into your existing structured data environment, leverage existing analytical infrastructure, and implement textual analytic processing technologies to solve new problems and uncover new opportunities. The book also covers new ways to integrate textual data into data warehouses, and new SQL techniques for reading and analyzing text. This book will be indispensable to every business and technical professional trying to make sense of a large body of unstructured text.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780137136889?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_pro_sql_server_2008_analytics_delivering_sales_and_marketing_dashboards">
<title>Pro SQL Server 2008 Analytics: Delivering Sales and Marketing Dashboards</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Brian Paulen; Jeff Finken</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Apress, March 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781430219286</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>300 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781430219286_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book provides everything you need to know to develop sophisticated and visually appealing sales and marketing dashboards using SQL Server 2008. It also covers how to integrate those dashboards with SharePoint, PerformancePoint, and other key Microsoft technologies. For analysts and executives, this book will provide the planning, requirement-gathering, and project management tools necessary to ensure your implementation goes smoothly. For developers, this book will enable you to further understand the tools available from Microsoft and how they can most successfully be implemented in your organization by beginning with basic steps and progressing to more advanced concepts. It is full of sensible concepts and direction for a successful analytics deployment based on the authors’ real-world analytics and CRM projects and experiences.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781430219286?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_progressive_methods_in_data_warehousing_and_business_intelligence_concepts_and_competitive_analytics">
<title>Progressive Methods in Data Warehousing and Business Intelligence: Concepts and Competitive Analytics</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By David Tanier</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IGI Global, February 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781605662329</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>390 pages, $195 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781605662329_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book covers the latest trends, studies, and developments in business intelligence and data warehousing. Consisting of four main sections, this book covers crucial topics within the field such as OLAP, spatio-temporal data warehousing, and benchmarking of the subject. Overall, this volume covers important foundations for researches and applications in data warehousing, covering modeling, OLAP and patterns, as well as new directions in benchmarking and evaluating data warehousing.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781605662329?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_business_analytics_for_managers_taking_business_intelligence_beyond_reporting">
<title>Business Analytics for Managers: Taking Business Intelligence beyond Reporting</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Gert H.N. Laursen; Jesper Thorlund</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, July 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470890615</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>272 pages, $49.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470890615_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Filled with examples and forward-thinking guidance from renowned BA leaders Gert Laursen and Jesper Thorlund, this book offers powerful techniques for making increasingly advanced use of information in order to survive any market conditions. Uncover tips for supporting your company’s ability to innovate in the future by using analytics and learn how to use information as a strategic asset. This book will help you improve your business’s decision making, align your business processes with your business’s objectives and drive your company into a prosperous future. This book will help you add tremendous value to your business.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470890615?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_your_google_game_plan_for_success_increasing_your_web_presence_with_google_adwords_analytics_and_website_optimizer">
<title>Your Google Game Plan for Success: Increasing Your Web Presence with Google AdWords, Analytics, and Website Optimizer</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Joe Teixeira</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Septembr 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470641644</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>456 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470641644_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Savvy marketers are always searching for new ways to attract and keep online customers. Google’s array of online tools plus the techniques and tips in this expert guide help you unlock the mystery of doing business in the digital age. Learn the basics of Google AdWords, Analytics, and Website Optimizer—and then discover how to use this powerful trifecta together to help you track, extract, and analyze data and make necessary changes. This book shows you how to use each of these tools individually, and then together as a powerful trio to track, analyze, and optimize your Web presence. You will learn how to install tracking code in your Web site, what reports are available and how to use them, testing, applying what you learn, and much more. Start increasing ROI, online sales, and web site traffic quality with Google tools and the insights and techniques in this expert guide.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470641644?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_deriving_intelligence_from_large_data_using_hadoop_and_applying_analytics">
<title>Deriving Intelligence from Large Data Using Hadoop and Applying Analytics</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Vineet Tyagi</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449306267</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>37 minutes, $9.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449306267_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Organizations today possess massive data - in tera- and petabytes - that needs to be effectively collected, stored and processed. Hadoop is a cost effective option that helps manage this big data. To derive real returns from these big data systems, one needs to extract useful insights and business intelligence, and this video will help you get started.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449306267?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_realtime_analytics_at_twitter">
<title>Realtime Analytics at Twitter</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Kevin Well</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449306199</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>42 minutes, $9.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449306199_xs.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Most analytics systems rely on large offline computations, which means results take hours or days. Twitter is all about realtime, but with over 160 million users producing over 90 million tweets per day, we need realtime analytics that scale horizontally. This video discusses the development of that infrastructure, as well as the products we are beginning to build on top of it.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/web-development/twitter/9781449306199">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_actionable_web_analytics_using_data_to_make_smart_business_decisions">
<title>Actionable Web Analytics: Using Data To Make Smart Business Decisions</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jason Burby; Shane Atchison; Jim Sterne</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Sybex, May 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470124741</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>288 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470124741_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Knowing everything you can about each click to your Web site can help you make strategic decisions regarding your business. This book is about the why, not just the how, of web analytics and the rules for developing a “culture of analysis” inside your organization. It answers why you should collect various types of data, why you need a strategy, why it must remain flexible and why your data must generate meaningful action. The authors use their decade of experience in Web analytics to answer all of these questions.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470124741?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_wordpress_for_business_bloggers_promote_and_grow_your_wordpress_blog_with_advanced_plugins_analytics_advertising_and_seo">
<title>WordPress for Business Bloggers: Promote and grow your WordPress blog with advanced plugins, analytics, advertising, and SEO</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Paul Thewlis</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Packt Publishing, August 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781847195326</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>356 pages, $35.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781847195326_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book will take you beyond the basics of WordPress, helping you take full advantage of its rich and powerful features to transform your basic blog into a more advanced and professional blog as quickly and painlessly as possible. You will learn everything you need to know to extend and grow your business blog. You will learn to mange the content including images and videos, which will make your blog more appealing. You’ll also learn how to market and measure the success of your blog using Google web applications and other popular tools. So, if want to transform your business blog to give a kick start to your business this book is for you.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781847195326?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_ibm_smart_analytics_system">
<title>IBM Smart Analytics System</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Whei-Jen Chen; Rafael Aielo; Silvio Luiz Correia Ferrari; Zohar Nissare-Houssen</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>IBM Redbooks, February 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780738435176</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>342 pages, $50.00 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/0738435171_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>The IBM Smart Analytics System is a fully-integrated and scalable data warehouse solution that combines software, server, and storage resources to offer optimal business intelligence and information management performance for enterprises. This IBM Redbook introduces the architecture and components of the IBM Smart Analytics System family, including its installation and configuration and show how to manage the systems effectively to deliver an enterprise class service. This book is targeted at the architects and specialists who need to know the concepts and the detailed instructions for a successful Smart Analytics System implementation and operation.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780738435176?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_statistics">
<title>Statistics</title>
<simpara>A major component in data analysis is statistics.  This section introduces the reader to statictics in a gentle fashion.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_head_first_statistics">
<title>Head First Statistics</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Dawn Griffith</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, August 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596527587</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>720 pages, $34.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596527587_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Wouldn’t it be great if there were a statistics book that made histograms, probability distributions, and chi square analysis more enjoyable than going to the dentist? Head First Statistics brings this typically dry subject to life, teaching you everything you want and need to know about statistics through engaging, interactive, and thought-provoking material, full of puzzles, stories, quizzes, visual aids, and real-world examples. Whether you’re a student, a professional, or just curious about statistical analysis, Head First’s brain-friendly formula helps you get a firm grasp of statistics so you can understand key points and actually use them. Learn to present data visually with charts and plots; discover the difference between taking the average with mean, median, and mode, and why it’s important; learn how to calculate probability and expectation; and much more. Head First Statistics is ideal for high school and college students taking statistics and satisfies the requirements for passing the College Board’s Advanced Placement (AP) Statistics Exam.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596527587?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_statistics_in_a_nutshell">
<title>Statistics in a Nutshell</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Sarah Boslaugh; Dr. Paul Andrew Watters</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, July 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596510497</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>478 pages, $34.99</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596510497_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Need to learn statistics as part of your job, or want some help passing a statistics course? Statistics in a Nutshell is a clear and concise introduction and reference that’s perfect for anyone with no previous background in the subject. This book gives you a solid understanding of statistics without being too simple, yet without the numbing complexity of most college texts. You get a firm grasp of the fundamentals and a hands-on understanding of how to apply them before moving on to the more advanced material that follows. Each chapter presents you with easy-to-follow descriptions illustrated by graphics, formulas, and plenty of solved examples. Before you know it, you’ll learn to apply statistical reasoning and statistical techniques, from basic concepts of probability and hypothesis testing to multivariate analysis.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596510497?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_probability_and_statistics_for_finance">
<title>Probability and Statistics for Finance</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Svetlozar T. Rachev; Markus Höechstöetter; Frank J. Fabozzi CFA; Sergio M. Focardi</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, September 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470400937</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>672 pages, $95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470400937_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book provides a comprehensive look at how probability and statistics is applied to the investment process. This book shows you how to apply quantitative methods to portfolios, in a clear, concise manner. Informative and accessible, this guide starts off with the basics and builds to an intermediate level of mastery. The authors cover a wide range of topics in this book, which can be used by all finance professionals as well as students aspiring to enter the field of finance.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470400937?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_the_complete_idiot_8217_s_guide_to_statistics_2nd_edition">
<title>The Complete Idiot’s Guide To Statistics, 2nd edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Robert Donnelly Jr.</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Alpha Books, May 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781592576340</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>416 pages, $19.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781592576340_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Aimed at high school and college students who need to take statistics to fulfill a degree requirement, this book follows a standard statistics curriculum with topics that include frequency distributions, probability, binomial distribution, poisson distribution, normal distribution, hypothesis testing, simple regression analysis, and more. Readers will find information on frequency distributions; mean, median, and mode; range, variance, and standard deviation; probability; and more.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781592576340?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_the_manga_guide_to_statistics">
<title>The Manga Guide to Statistics</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Shin Takahashi</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>No Starch Press, October 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781593271893</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>224 pages, $19.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781593271893_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book will teach you everything you need to know about statistics, while entertaining you at the same time. With its unique combination of Japanese-style comics called manga and serious educational content, the EduManga format is already a hit in Japan. Reluctant statistics students of all ages will enjoy learning along with Rui, the main character, in this charming, easy-to-read guide, which uses real-world examples like teen magazine quizzes, bowling games, test scores, and ramen noodle prices. Examples, exercises, and answer keys help you follow along and check your work. An appendix showing how to perform statistics calculations in Microsoft Excel makes it easy to put Rui’s lessons into practice. This EduManga book is a translation from a bestselling series in Japan, co-published with Ohmsha, Ltd. of Tokyo, Japan.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781593271893?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_elementary_statistics_using_sas">
<title>Elementary Statistics Using SAS</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By SAS Publishing</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>SAS Publishing, October 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781607643791</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>560 pages, $59.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781607643791_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Bridging the gap between statistics texts and SAS documentation, this book is written for those who want to perform analyses to solve problems. The book explains the basics of SAS data sets and shows how to use SAS for descriptive statistics and graphs. It also covers fundamental statistical concepts, including normality and hypothesis testing. It even shows analyses for comparing two groups, comparing multiple groups, fitting regression equations, and exploring contingency tables. For each analysis, the author explains the assumptions, statistical approach, and SAS methods and syntax, and makes conclusions from the results. Statistical methods covered include two-sample t-tests, paired-difference t-tests, analysis of variance, multiple comparison techniques, regression, regression diagnostics, and chi-square tests.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781607643791?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_even_you_can_learn_statistics_a_guide_for_everyone_who_has_ever_been_afraid_of_statistics_second_edition">
<title>Even You Can Learn Statistics: A Guide for Everyone Who Has Ever Been Afraid of Statistics, Second Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By David M. Levine Ph.D.; David F. Stephan</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>FT Press, August 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780137025961</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>384 pages, $19.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780137025961_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This fully updated book teaches you all the statistical techniques you’ll need for finance, quality, marketing, the social sciences, or anything else! Simple jargon-free explanations help you understand every technique. Practical examples and worked-out problems give you hands-on practice. This edition delivers new examples, more detailed problems and sample solutions, plus an all-new chapter on powerful multiple regression techniques.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780137025961?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_statistics_hacks">
<title>Statistics Hacks</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Bruce Frey</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, May 2006</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596101640</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>360 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/0596101643_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>These cool tips, tricks, and mind-boggling solutions from the world of statistics, measurement, and research methods will not only amaze and entertain you, but will give you an advantage in several real-world situations-including business. This book is ideal for anyone who likes puzzles, brainteasers, games, gambling, magic tricks, and those who want to apply math and science to everyday circumstances. Statistics Hacks presents useful techniques from statistics, educational and psychological measurement, and experimental research to help you solve a variety of problems in business, games, and life. Whether you’re a statistics enthusiast who does calculations in your sleep or a civilian who is entertained by clever solutions to interesting problems, Statistics Hacks has tools to give you an edge over the world’s slim odds.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/statistics/0596101643?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_statistical_analysis_microsoft_excel_2010">
<title>Statistical Analysis: Microsoft Excel 2010</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Conrad Carlbert</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Que, April 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780132681872</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>464 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780132681872_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Use Excel 2010’s powerful statistical tools to gain a deeper understanding of your data, make more accurate and reliable inferences, and solve problems in fields ranging from business to health sciences with this book. Top Excel guru Conrad Carlberg shows how to use Excel 2010 to perform the core statistical tasks every business professional, student, and researcher should master. Using real-world examples, Carlberg helps you choose the right technique for each problem and get the most out of Excel’s statistical features, including its new consistency functions. Along the way, you discover the most effective ways to use correlation and regression and analysis of variance and covariance. You see how to use Excel to test statistical hypotheses using the normal, binomial, t and F distributions.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780132681872?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_statistical_analysis_with_r_2">
<title>Statistical Analysis with R</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By John M. Quick</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Packt Publishing, October 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781849512084</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>300 pages, $40.49 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781849512084_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Without any prior experience in programming or statistical software, this book will help you quickly become a knowledgeable user of R. This book will take you on a journey as the strategist for an ancient Chinese kingdom. Along the way, you will learn how to use R to arrive at practical solutions and how to effectively communicate your results. Ultimately, the fate of the kingdom depends upon your ability to make informed, data-driven decisions with R.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/programming/r/9781849512084">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_common_statistical_methods_for_clinical_research_with_sas_examples_third_edition">
<title>Common Statistical Methods for Clinical Research with SAS Examples, Third Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Glenn Walker; Jack Shostak</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>SAS Publishing, February 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781607642282</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>552 pages, $79.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781607642282_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This Third Edition is a thoroughly updated edition of the popular introductory statistics book for clinical researchers. This new edition has been extensively updated to include the use of ODS graphics in numerous examples as well as a new emphasis on PROC MIXED. Straightforward and easy to use as either a text or a reference, the book is full of practical examples from clinical research to illustrate both statistical and SAS methodology. Each example is worked out completely, step by step, from the raw data. This book is an applications book with minimal theory that drills down into details that will be valuable to statistical analysts and programmers. Further details, as well as bonus information and a guide to further reading, are presented in the extensive appendices. This text is a one-source guide for statisticians that documents the use of the tests used most often in clinical research, with assumptions, details, and some tricks—all in one place.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781607642282?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_think_stats">
<title>Think Stats</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Allen Downey</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, July 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449307110</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>140 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449308117_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This is a textbook for a new kind of introductory prob-stat class. It emphasizes the use of statistics to explore large datasets. It takes a computation approach, allowing students to run experiments to test statistical behavior, run simulations, and use discrete distributions and computations. Because students work in a general-purpose programming language (Python), they are able to import data from almost any source, since they aren’t limited to data that has been cleaned and formatted for a particular statistics tool. The book lends itself to a project-based approach, where sutdents must pose a statistical question, find a dataset that can address it, and apply each of the techniques they learn to their own data. To demonstrate the kind of analysis for students, the book presents a case study that runs through all of the chapters.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/-/9781449308117?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_cloud_services_amp_infrastructure">
<title>Cloud Services &amp; Infrastructure</title>
<sect1 id="_cloud_computing_bible">
<title>Cloud Computing Bible</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Barrie Sosinsky</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, January 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470903568</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>525 pages, $44.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470903568_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Because cloud computing involves various technologies, protocols, platforms, and infrastructure elements, this comprehensive reference is just what you need if you’ll be using or implementing cloud computing. Cloud computing offers significant cost savings by eliminating upfront expenses for hardware and software. Anyone involved with planning, implementing, using, or maintaining a cloud computing project will rely on the information found in this book.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470903568?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_cloud_computing_for_dummies">
<title>Cloud Computing For Dummies</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Judith Hurwitz; Robin Bloor; Marcia Kaufman; Fern Halper</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>For Dummies, November 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470484708</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>336 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470484708_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Cloud computing can be difficult to understand at first, but the cost-saving possibilities are great and many companies are getting on board. If you’ve been put in charge of implementing a cloud computing solution, this straightforward, plain-English guide clears up the confusion and helps you get your plan in place. You’ll learn how cloud computing enables you to run a more green IT infrastructure, and access technology-enabled services from the Internet (“in the cloud”) without having to understand, manage, or invest in the technology infrastructure that supports them. You’ll also find out what you need to consider when implementing a plan, how to handle security issues, and more.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470484708?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_cloud_application_architectures">
<title>Cloud Application Architectures</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By George Reese</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, April 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596157647</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>208 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596157647_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>If you’re involved in planning IT infrastructure as a network or system architect, system administrator, or developer, this book will help you adapt your skills to work with these highly scalable, highly redundant infrastructure services. While analysts hotly debate the advantages and risks of cloud computing, IT staff and programmers are left to determine whether and how to put their applications into these virtualized services. This book provides answers — and critical guidance — on issues of cost, availability, performance, scaling, privacy, and security. To provide realistic examples of the book’s principles in action, the author delves into some of the choices and operations available on Amazon Web Services, and includes high-level summaries of several of the other services available on the market today. This book provides best practices that apply to every available cloud service. Learn how to make the transition to the cloud and prepare your web applications to succeed.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596157647?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_test_driven_infrastructure_with_chef">
<title>Test-Driven Infrastructure with Chef</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Stephen Nelson-Smith</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, June 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449309718</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>88 pages, $24.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449309718_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>The advent of modern programming frameworks such as Rails and Django, together with the ready availability of virtualization, and the explosion of interest in configuration management tools such as Puppet and Chef has revolutionized the web operations world. In this book, the author makes a case for introducing acceptance test driven infrastructure development as a way to deliver value and reduce risk. Developing infrastructure with Opscode Chef, and testing it using Cucumber, he explains how to build a test environment that allows end-to-end testing of the whole infrastructure to tease out dependencies and hidden side effects.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781449309718?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_host_your_web_site_in_the_cloud_amazon_web_services_made_easy_1ed">
<title>Host Your Web Site In The Cloud: Amazon Web Services Made Easy, 1Ed</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jeffrey Barr</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>SitePoint, September 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780980576832</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>300 pages, $39.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780980576832_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is a step-by-step guide to hosting web sites on Amazon EC2. Authored by Jeffrey Barr, it covers all aspects of cloud hosting and migrating your existing applications and websites to the Cloud. This book is aimed at web developers who have built a web application or two, and are ready to leap into the world of cloud computing using Amazon Web Services. This book makes use of the PHP language, and it is assumed that you know the fundamentals of HTML and CSS, and that you’re comfortable with the Linux command line. By the end of this book, you can expect to have a firm grasp of the concept of cloud computing and its role in enabling a whole new class of scalable and reliable web applications. You’ll also have gained a clear understanding of the range of Amazon Web Services, such as the Simple Storage Service, the Elastic Compute Cloud, the Simple Queue Service, and SimpleDB. You’ll be able to make use of all these services in your web applications as you write commands, tools, and processes in PHP.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780980576832?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_securing_the_cloud_cloud_computer_security_techniques_and_tactics">
<title>Securing the Cloud: Cloud Computer Security Techniques and Tactics</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Vic J.R. Winkler</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Syngress, April 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781597495929</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>315 pages, $59.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781597495929_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is a practical resource for anyone who is considering using, building, or securing a cloud implementation. Cloud infrastructure engineers, cloud services engineers, and integrators will find value in learning about relevant security approaches and cloud security architecture. It will also provide value to those who are interested in understanding cloud security. Executive-level management will gain an understanding of the security advantages and developing trends that are likely to mature as cloud computing progresses.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781597495929?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_automated_infrastructure_is_on_the_menu_with_chef">
<title>Automated Infrastructure is on the Menu with Chef</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Joshua Timberman; Aaron Peterson</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, July 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449396497</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>2 hours 3 minutes, $79.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449396497_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>As application infrastructures become increasingly complex, the need for a cohesive, integrated deployment and configuration solution becomes apparent. The era of 6 week server deployments is gone in a world where new computing resources are an API call away. Modern infrastructures need an API, so systems can be automated easier. Chef provides abstraction and an API so system administrators write simple code that describes the roles, recipes and resources that should be applied to systems. Chef is an open source system integration framework, built to bring the benefits of configuration management to an entire infrastructure, and this book will help you learn everything you need to know when using Chef.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449396497?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_cloud_security_and_privacy">
<title>Cloud Security and Privacy</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Tim Mather; Subra Kumaraswamy; Shahed Latif</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, September 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596806453</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>336 pages, $34.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596806453_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>You may regard cloud computing as an ideal way for your company to control IT costs, but do you know how private and secure this service really is? Not many people do. With this book, you’ll learn what’s at stake when you trust your data to the cloud, and what you can do to keep your virtual infrastructure and web applications secure. Ideal for IT staffers, information security and privacy practitioners, business managers, service providers, and investors alike, this book offers you sound advice from three well-known authorities in the tech security world. You’ll learn detailed information on cloud computing security that-until now-has been sorely lacking.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596806453?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_cloud_computing_and_soa_convergence_in_your_enterprise_a_step_by_step_guide">
<title>Cloud Computing and SOA Convergence in Your Enterprise: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By David S. Linthicum</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Addison-Wesley Professional, September 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780321659392</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>264 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780321659392_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Massive, disruptive change is coming to IT as Software as a Service (SaaS), SOA, mashups, Web 2.0, and cloud computing truly come of age. Writing for IT executives, architects, and developers alike, David S. Linthicum explains why the days of managing IT organizations as private fortresses will rapidly disappear as IT inevitably becomes a global community. He demonstrates how to run IT when critical elements of customer, product, and business data and processes extend far beyond the firewall. He also shows how to use all of that information to deliver real-time answers about everything from an individual customer’s credit to the location of a specific cargo container. This book offers a clear-eyed assessment of the challenges associated with this new world—and offers a step-by-step program for getting there with a maximum return on investment at a minimum risk.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780321659392?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_a_quick_start_guide_to_cloud_computing_moving_your_business_into_the_cloud">
<title>A Quick Start Guide to Cloud Computing: Moving your Business into the Cloud</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Mark I. Williams</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Kogan Page, November 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780749461300</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>151 pages, $14.95 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780749461300_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book cuts through the industry hype and confusion surrounding cloud computing, creating an understanding and helping executives to select those cloud computing solutions and service providers that can best improve the way they do business. If you are involved in directing IT strategy, this book contains tips, tools and checklists that can help you make the right choices for your business and reject solutions that fix problems you do not have.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780749461300?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_the_cloud_at_your_service_the_when_how_and_why_of_enterprise_cloud_computing">
<title>The Cloud at Your Service: The when, how, and why of enterprise cloud computing</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jothy Rosenberg; Arthur Mateos</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Manning Publications, October 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781935182528</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>200 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781935182528_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>As an economically viable way for businesses of all sizes to distribute computing, cloud computing shows tremendous promise. But the intense hype surrounding the Cloud is making it next to impossible for responsible IT managers and business decision-makers to get a clear understanding of what the Cloud really means, what it might do for them, when it is practical, and what their future with the Cloud looks like. This book helps cut through all of this fog to help enterprises make critical decisions based upon facts and the authors’ informed unbiased recommendations and predictions.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781935182528?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_soa_governance_governing_shared_services_on_premise_and_in_the_cloud">
<title>SOA Governance: Governing Shared Services On-Premise and in the Cloud</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Thomas Erl; Stephen G. Bennett; Clive Gee; Benjamin Carlyle; Robert Laird; Anne Thomas Manes; Robert Moores; Robert Schneider; Leo Shuster; Andre Tost; Chris Venable; Filippos Santas</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Prentice Hall, April 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780132478373</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>704 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780132478373_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Authored by world-renowned experts in the fields of SOA, IT governance, and cloud computing, this comprehensive book provides clear direction as to what does and does not constitute SOA governance and then steps the reader through the most important industry governance practices, as they pertain to individual SOA project lifecycle stages. With a consistent, vendor-neutral focus, and with the help of case study examples, the authors demonstrate how to define and position precepts, organizational roles, processes, standards, and metrics. You will benefit from thorough and visually depicted cross-references and mapping between roles, processes, precepts, and project stages, enabling you to fully explore dynamics and dependencies and thereby learn how to use these governance controls to create your own custom SOA governance systems. This important title will be valuable to every practitioner concerned with making SOA work, including senior IT managers, project managers, architects, analysts, developers, administrators, QA professionals, security specialists, and cloud computing professionals.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780132478373?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_building_applications_in_the_cloud_concepts_patterns_and_projects">
<title>Building Applications in the Cloud: Concepts, Patterns, and Projects</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Christopher M. Moyer</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Addison-Wesley Professional, April 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780132107891</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>400 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780132107891_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Putting your company’s applications in the cloud will no doubt save your IT department time and money — but it’s very often a more challenging proposition than you might expect. With this book, Chris Moyer has created a handy reference of patterns and techniques to properly leverage the benefits the cloud can provide. Readers who have been handed a project and told to “make it scale” can flip through the patterns provided here to get ideas and see what fits the project at hand. Use this book to get a lay of the land and guide your cloud project to successful scalability.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780132107891?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_cloud_security_a_comprehensive_guide_to_secure_cloud_computing">
<title>Cloud Security: A Comprehensive Guide to Secure Cloud Computing</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Ronald L. Krutz; Russell Dean Vines</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, August 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470589878</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>384 pages, $50.00 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470589878_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Cloud computing allows both large and small organizations to have the opportunity to use Internet-based services so that they can reduce start-up costs, lower capital expenditures, use services on a pay-as-you-use basis, access applications only as needed, and quickly reduce or increase capacities. These benefits, however, are accompanied by a myriad of security issues, and this valuable book tackles the most common security challenges that cloud computing faces. The authors offer you years of unparalleled expertise and knowledge as they discuss the extremely challenging topics of data ownership, privacy protections, data mobility, quality of service and service levels, bandwidth costs, data protection, and support. As the most current and complete guide to helping you find your way through a maze of security minefields, this book is mandatory reading if you are involved in any aspect of cloud computing.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470589878?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_cloud_computing_web_based_applications_that_change_the_way_you_work_and_collaborate_online">
<title>Cloud Computing: Web-Based Applications That Change the Way You Work and Collaborate Online</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Michael Miller</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Que, August 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780768686227</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>312 pages, $24.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780768686227_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>With cloud computing, everything you do is now web-based instead of being desktop-based; you can access all your programs and documents from any computer that’s connected to the Internet. Whether you want to share photographs with your family, coordinate volunteers for a community organization, or manage a multi-faceted project in a large organization, cloud computing can help you do it more easily than ever before. If you want to learn about cloud computing, start with this book.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780768686227?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_development_with_the_force_com_platform_building_business_applications_in_the_cloud_second_edition">
<title>Development with the Force.com Platform: Building Business Applications in the Cloud, Second Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jason Ouellette</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Addison-Wesley Professional, July 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780321767356</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>496 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780132685047_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This is the first book that brings together all of the practical, technical guidance you need to make the most of Force.com in your own custom enterprise applications. Leading Force.com developer Jason Ouellette helps you identify suitable uses for Force.com and provides all of the insights and sample code needed to rapidly prototype, deploy, and integrate with production-quality Force.com applications. Ouellette provides realistic code examples at every step, emphasizing maintainability, flexibility, and interoperability throughout.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780321767356?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_cloud_computing_with_amazon_web_services_livelessons">
<title>Cloud Computing with Amazon Web Services LiveLessons</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Bernard Golden; Jorge Noa</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Addison-Wesley Professional, July 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780321705563</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>5 hours 34 minutes, $49.50 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780321705563_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Cloud computing expert Bernard Golden provides easy-to-follow instructions in this video that will allow you to get up and running with the Amazon Web Services platform in no time. This video covers three key elements of working with AWS: Creating, launching, and shutting down EC2 instances; Storage and persistence in AWS environments; and managing AWS-based instances and managing applications in AWS environments. Further, this video provides a set of best practices for working with S3, Elastic Book Store, and SimpleDB.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9780321705563?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_silver_clouds_dark_linings_a_concise_guide_to_cloud_computing">
<title>Silver Clouds, Dark Linings: A Concise Guide to Cloud Computing</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Archie Reed; Stephen G. Bennett</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Prentice Hall, September 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780132599672</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>178 pages</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780132599672_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>In this concise, executive level book, leading experts Archie Reed and Stephen G. Bennett share the insights and guidance decision-makers need to drive maximum value from cloud services—and avoid the pitfalls.The authors explain what cloud computing is, how it works, who provides cloud services, and how companies are using them. They walk through the entire cloud lifecycle, offering expert guidance on planning, governance, compliance, security, operations, administration, management, and more.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780132599672?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_developing_applications_for_the_cloud_on_the_microsoft_windows_azure_platform">
<title>Developing Applications for the Cloud on the Microsoft Windows Azure Platform</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Eugenio Pace; Dominic Betts; Scott Densmore; Ryan Dunn; Masashi Narumoto; Matias Woloski</emphasis>
<emphasis>Microsoft Press, November 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780735656239</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>168 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780735656239_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book demonstrates how you can create from scratch a multi-tenant, Software as a Service (SaaS) application to run in the cloud by using the latest versions of the Windows Azure tools and the latest features of the Windows Azure platform. The book is intended for any architect, developer, or information technology (IT) professional who designs, builds, or operates applications and services that run on or interact with the cloud. Although applications do not need to be based on the Microsoft Windows operating system to work in Windows Azure, this book is written for people who work with Windows-based systems.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780735656239?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_moving_applications_to_the_cloud">
<title>Moving Applications to the Cloud</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Eugenio Pace; Dominic Betts; Scott Densmore; Ryan Dunn; Masashi Narumoto; Matias Woloski</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Microsoft Press, September 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780735651784</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>176 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780735651784_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is the first volume in a planned series about the Windows Azure platform and focuses on a migration scenario. It introduces a fictitious company named Adatum, which step-by-step modifies its expense tracking and reimbursement system, aExpense, so that it can be deployed to Windows Azure. Each chapter explores different considerations: authentication and authorization, data access, session management, deployment, development life cycle and cost analysis.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780735651784?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_amazon_web_services_ec2_s3_emr_amp_simpledb">
<title>Amazon Web Services: EC2, S3, EMR, &amp; SimpleDB</title>
<simpara>This sections covers topics from the most popular cloud computing provider: Amazon Web Services.  Titles introduce readers to AWS and
show them how to port existing applications to AWS.   Other titles in this section provide detailed instruction into services that AWS
provides.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_programming_amazon_ec2">
<title>Programming Amazon EC2</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jurg van Vliet; Flavia Paganelli</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449303617</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>184 pages, $34.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449303617_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>If you plan to build applications to run on Amazon’s Web Services, this is precisely the book you need. Programming Amazon EC2 provides architects, developers, and administrators with an end-to-end approach to designing and building a practical application on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2), a central part of the AWS platform. You’ll focus on critical issues such as load balancing, scaling, monitoring, and automation in the process.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781449303617?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_amazon_web_services_migrating_your_net_enterprise_application">
<title>Amazon Web Services: Migrating your .NET Enterprise Application</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Rob Linton</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Packt Publishing, July 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781849681940</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>336 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781849681940_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This step-by-step guide to moving your Enterprise .NET application to Amazon covers not only the concept, technical design, and strategy, but also enlightens you about the business strategy and in-depth implementation details involved in moving an application to Amazon. You’ll discover how to map your requirements against the Amazon Cloud, as well as secure and enhance your application with AWS. After comparing the existing application with the newly migrated version, it then moves on to explain how to make the hosted application better. It covers how to leverage some of the scalability and redundancy built into the Cloud, and along the way you’ll learn about all of the major AWS products like EC2, S3, and EBS.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781849681940?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_programming_amazon_web_services_1st_edition">
<title>Programming Amazon Web Services, 1st edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By James Murty</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596515812</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>608 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596515812_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book demonstrates how developers working with small- to mid-sized companies can take advantage of Amazon Web Services (AWS) such as the Simple Storage Service (S3), Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2), Simple Queue Service (SQS), Flexible Payments Service (FPS), and SimpleDB to build web-scale business applications. With AWS, Amazon offers a new paradigm for IT infrastructure: use what you need, as you need it, and pay as you go. This book explains how you can access Amazon’s open APIs to store and run applications, rather than spend precious time and resources building your own. Whether you’re starting a new online business, need to ramp up existing services, or require an offsite backup for your home, this book gives you the background and the practical knowledge you need to start using AWS. Other books explain how to build web services. This book teaches businesses how to take make use of existing services from an established technology leader.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596515812?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_amazon_simpledb_developer_guide">
<title>Amazon SimpleDB Developer Guide</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Prabhakar Chaganti; Rich Helms</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Packt Publishing, June 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781847197344</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>252 pages, $35.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781847197344_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This practical book aims to address your preconceptions on how SimpleDB will work for you. You will be quickly led through the differences between relational databases and SimpleDB, and the implications of using SimpleDB. Throughout this book, there is an emphasis on demonstrating key concepts with practical examples for Java, PHP, and Python developers. You will be introduced to this massively scalable schema-less key-value data store: what it is, how it works, and why it is such a game-changer. You will then explore the basic functionality offered by SimpleDB including querying, code samples, and a lot more. This book will help you deploy services outside the Amazon cloud and access them from any web host.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781847197344?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_elastic_beanstalk">
<title>Elastic Beanstalk</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jurg van Vliet; Flavia Paganelli; Steven van Wel; Dara Dowd</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, July 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: : 9781449306649</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>86 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449309558_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>While it has always been possible to run Java applications on EC2, Elastic Beanstalk makes it trivially simple. This book shows Java developers how to take advantage of EBS to automate deploying their applications to the cloud.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/-/9781449309558">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_hadoop_amp_related_projects_nutch_solr_lucene_hive_zookeeper_pig">
<title>Hadoop &amp; Related Projects (Nutch, Solr, Lucene, Hive, Zookeeper, Pig)</title>
<simpara>The Apache Hadoop project is an open-source software framework for distributed computing.  Topics in this section show devlopers how to
solve big data problems with this framework.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_hadoop_the_definitive_guide">
<title>Hadoop: The Definitive Guide</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Tom White</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, October 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449398644</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>626 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449398644_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Apache Hadoop is ideal for organizations with a growing need to store and process massive application datasets. With this book developers will find details for analyzing large datasets with Hadoop, and administrators will learn how to set up and run Hadoop clusters. The book includes case studies that illustrate how Hadoop is used to solve specific problems.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781449398644?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_hadoop_in_action">
<title>Hadoop in Action</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Chuck Lam</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Manning Publications, December 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781935182191</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>336 pages, $44.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781935182191_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book leads you from obtaining a copy of Hadoop to setting it up in a cluster and writing data analytic programs. The book begins by making the basic idea of Hadoop and MapReduce easier to grasp by applying the default Hadoop installation to a few easy-to-follow tasks, such as analyzing changes in word frequency across a body of documents. The book continues through the basic concepts of MapReduce applications developed using Hadoop, including a close look at framework components, use of Hadoop for a variety of data analysis tasks, and numerous examples of Hadoop in action. This book takes you beyond the mechanics of running Hadoop, teaching you to write meaningful programs in a MapReduce framework.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781935182191?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_pro_hadoop">
<title>Pro Hadoop</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jason Venner</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Apress, June 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781430219422</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>440 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781430219422_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book brings you up to speed on Hadoop. You learn the ins and outs of MapReduce; how to structure a cluster, design, and implement the Hadoop file system; and how to build your first cloud–computing tasks using Hadoop. Learn how to let Hadoop take care of distributing and parallelizing your software—you just focus on the code, Hadoop takes care of the rest. Written from the perspective of a principal engineer with down–in–the–trenches knowledge of what to do wrong with Hadoop, you learn how to avoid the common, expensive first errors that everyone makes with creating their own Hadoop system or inheriting someone else’s.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781430219422?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_how_to_develop_big_data_applications_for_hadoop">
<title>How to Develop Big Data Applications for Hadoop</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Ken Krugler; Shevek M; Chris Wensel; Abe Taha</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, February 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449305796</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Running Time: 2 hours 25 minutes, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449305796_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Distributed applications running on Hadoop clusters can deliver powerful insights and results from the biggest data sets ever generated. But do you have to be a rocket scientist to use it? Fortunately, the answer is no. This video will explain the theory of MapReduce and how to develop big data applications in Java and higher level languages such as Pig and Hive SQL.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449305796?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_deriving_intelligence_from_large_data_using_hadoop_and_applying_analytics_2">
<title>Deriving Intelligence from Large Data Using Hadoop and Applying Analytics</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Vineet Tyagi</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449306267</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Running Time: 37 minutes, $9.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449306267_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Organizations today possess massive data - in tera- and petabytes - that needs to be effectively collected, stored and processed. Hadoop is a cost effective option that helps manage this big data. To derive real returns from these big data systems, one needs to extract useful insights and business intelligence, and this video is the place to look for this information.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449306267?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_lucene_in_action_second_edition">
<title>Lucene in Action, Second Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Michael McCandless; Erik Hatcher; Otis Gospodnetic</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Manning Publications, May 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781933988177</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>475 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781933988177_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Lucene now powers search in diverse companies including Akamai, Netflix, LinkedIn, Technorati, HotJobs, Epiphany, FedEx, Mayo Clinic, MIT, New Scientist Magazine, and many others. Lucene still delivers high-performance search features in a disarmingly easy-to-use API. Due to its vibrant and diverse open-source community of developers and users, Lucene is relentlessly improving, with evolutions to APIs, significant new features such as payloads, and a huge increase (as much as 8x) in indexing speed with Lucene 2.3. And with clear writing, reusable examples, and unmatched advice on best practices, this book continues to be the definitive guide to developing with Lucene.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781933988177?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_solr_1_4_enterprise_search_server">
<title>Solr 1.4 Enterprise Search Server</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By David Smiley; Eric Pugh</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Packt Publishing, August 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781847195883</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>336 pages, $44.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781847195883_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>If you are a developer building a high-traffic web site, you need to have a terrific search engine. Sites like Netflix.com and Zappos.com employ Solr, an open source enterprise search server, which uses and extends the Lucene search library. This book is a comprehensive reference guide for every feature Solr has to offer. It serves the reader right from initiation to development to deployment. It also comes with complete running examples to demonstrate its use and show how to integrate it with other languages and frameworks.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781847195883?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_real_time_searching_of_big_data_with_solr_and_hadoop">
<title>Real-Time Searching of Big Data with Solr and Hadoop</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Rod Cope</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449306090</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Running Time: 47 minutes, $9.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449306090_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Hadoop and HBase make it easy to store terabytes of data, but how do you scale your search mechanism to sift through these mountains of bits and retrieve large result sets in a matter of milliseconds? Careful use of the Solr search server, based on Lucene, made these requirements come to life in the production environment found in this video. Come learn how we query terabytes of data in a highly available system.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449306090?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_avro_data">
<title>Avro Data</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Doug Cutting</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449306113</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Running Time: 47 minutes, $9.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449306113_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Apache Avro provides an expressive, efficient standard for representing large data sets. Avro data is programming-language neutral and MapReduce-friendly. Hopefully it can replace gzipped CSV-like formats as a dominant format for data. Take a look at this video to learn more.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449306113?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_mysql">
<title>MySQL</title>
<simpara>MySQL is a tried and true open source database.  This section presents titles that readers can leverage to get the most of MySQL</simpara>
<sect1 id="_high_performance_mysql_second_edition">
<title>High Performance MySQL, Second Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Baron Schwartz; Peter Zaitsev; Vadim Tkachenko; Jeremy D. Zawodny; Arjen Lentz; Derek J. Balling</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, June 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596101718</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>712 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596101718_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is the definitive guide to building fast, reliable systems with MySQL. Written by noted experts with years of real-world experience building very large systems, this book covers every aspect of MySQL performance in detail, and focuses on robustness, security, and data integrity. It teaches you advanced techniques in depth so you can bring out MySQL’s full power. Learn how to design schemas, indexes, queries and advanced MySQL features for maximum performance, and get detailed guidance for tuning your MySQL server, operating system, and hardware to their fullest potential. You’ll also learn practical, safe, high-performance ways to scale your applications with replication, load balancing, high availability, and failover. This second edition is completely revised and greatly expanded, with deeper coverage in all areas.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596101718?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_mysql_administrator_8217_s_bible">
<title>MySQL Administrator’s Bible</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Sheeri K. Cabral; Keith Murphy</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, May 2009</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470416914</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>888 pages, $49.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780470416914_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>With special focus on the next major release of MySQL, this book provides a solid framework for anyone new to MySQL or transitioning from another database platform, as well as experienced MySQL administrators. The high-profile author duo provides essential coverage of the fundamentals of MySQL database management—including MySQL’s unique approach to basic database features and functions—as well as coverage of SQL queries, data and index types, stores procedure and functions, triggers and views, and transactions. They also present comprehensive coverage of such topics as MySQL server tuning, managing storage engines, caching, backup and recovery, managing users, index tuning, database and performance monitoring, security, and more.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780470416914?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_mysql_fourth_edition">
<title>MySQL, Fourth Edition</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Paul DuBois</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Addison-Wesley Professional, August 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780768678673</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>1224 pages, $54.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780768678673_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>In this book, Paul DuBois provides a comprehensive guide to using and administering MySQL effectively and productively. He describes everything from the basics of getting information into a database and formulating queries, to using MySQL with PHP or Perl to generate dynamic web pages, to writing your own programs that access MySQL databases, to administering MySQL servers. The fourth edition of this bestselling book has been meticulously revised and updated to thoroughly cover the latest features and capabilities of MySQL 5.0, as well as to add new coverage of features introduced with MySQL 5.1.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780768678673?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_mysql_5_0_certification_study_guide">
<title>MySQL 5.0 Certification Study Guide</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Paul DuBois; Stefan Hinz; Carsten Pedersen</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>MySQL Press, August 2005</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780672328121</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>672 pages, $64.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/0672328127_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This is the official guide to passing the two MySQL certification tests for MySQL 5, the long-awaited major revision of MySQL. MySQL professionals need a way to distinguish themselves from the vast majority of database administrators and developers. With more than 4 million active installations, MySQL is the world’s most popular open-source database. The MySQL certification tests, available at over 3,000 PearsonVUE testing centers, is a key component of this enterprise growth strategy, establishing a base level of skills for database users, administrators and programmers. This book is a reliable way for MySQL users, developers, and administrators to prepare for either of the MySQL tests.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780672328121?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_learning_mysql">
<title>Learning MySQL</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Seyed M.M. Tahaghoghi; Hugh E. Williams</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, November 2006</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596008642</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>624 pages, $44.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/0596008643_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This densely packed book includes detailed instructions to help you set up and design an effective database, create powerful queries using SQL, configure MySQL for improved security, and squeeze information out of your data. After covering the basics, the book travels far into MySQL’s subtleties, including complex queries and joins, how to interact with the database over the Web using PHP or Perl, and important house-keeping such as backups and security.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596008642?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_no_sql_data_stores_mongodb_cassandra">
<title>No SQL Data Stores (MongoDB, Cassandra)</title>
<simpara>Massive amounts of data call for new methods of not only processing but also storing data.  This section covers titles which use No SQL
technology to store massive amounts of data.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_the_definitive_guide_to_mongodb_the_nosql_database_for_cloud_and_desktop_computing">
<title>The Definitive Guide to MongoDB: The NoSQL Database for Cloud and Desktop Computing</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Eelco Plugge; Peter Membrey; Tim Hawkins</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Apress, September 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781430230519</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>327 pages, $44.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781430230519_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>MongoDB, a cross-platform NoSQL database, is the fastest-growing new database in the world. MongoDB provides a rich document orientated structure with dynamic queries that you’ll recognize from RDMBS offerings such as MySQL. This is a book about a NoSQL database that does not require the SQL crowd to re-learn how the database world works, since MongoDB has reached 1.0 and already boasts 50,000+ users. The community is strong and vibrant and MongoDB is improving at a fast rate. With scalable and fast databases becoming critical for today’s applications, this book shows you how to install, administer and program MongoDB without pretending SQL never existed.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781430230519?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_building_a_nosql_data_cloud">
<title>Building a NoSQL Data Cloud</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Krishna Sankar</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, July 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449396428</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Running Time: 2 hours 57 minutes, $99.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449396428_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This video provides an in-depth tutorial on various forms of NOSQL (NotOnlySQL) datastores (key/value, data structure store, document store and wide column stores) for working with semi-structured data. The data ranges from web logs to social and knowledge graphs to configuration data stores for cloud infrastructures and other domains.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449396428?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_cassandra_the_definitive_guide">
<title>Cassandra: The Definitive Guide</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Eben Hewitt</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, December 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449399764</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>336 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449399764_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>The rising popularity of Apache Cassandra rests on its ability to handle very large data sets that include hundreds of terabytes — and that’s why this distributed database has been chosen by organizations such as Facebook, Twitter, Digg, and Rackspace. With this hands-on guide, you’ll get all the details and practical examples you need to understand Cassandra’s non-relational database design and put it to work in a production environment. The author pays special attention to data modeling, and demonstrates Cassandra’s many advantages, including its high availability, eventual consistency model, and ability to scale easily. If you’re a developer with a startup, you’ll learn how to future-proof your application by implementing Cassandra before your storage needs become critical. Join the growing list data-intensive organizations that have come to rely on Cassandra’s design.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781449399764?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_cassandra_high_performance_cookbook">
<title>Cassandra High Performance Cookbook</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Edward Capriolo</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Packt Publishing, July 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781849515122</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>324 pages, $40.49 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781849515122_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Apache Cassandra is a fault-tolerant, distributed data store which offers linear scalability allowing it to be a storage platform for large high volume websites. This book provides detailed recipes that describe how to use the features of Cassandra and improve its performance. Recipes cover topics ranging from setting up Cassandra for the first time to complex multiple data center installations. The recipe format presents the information in a concise actionable form. The book describes in detail how features of Cassandra can be tuned and what the possible effects of tuning can be. Recipes include how to access data stored in Cassandra and use third party tools to help you out. The book also describes how to monitor and do capacity planning to ensure it is performing at a high level. Towards the end, it takes you through the use of libraries and third party applications with Cassandra and Cassandra integration with Hadoop.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781849515122?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_hands_on_cassandra">
<title>Hands-on Cassandra</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Eric Evans</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, July 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449396404</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Running Time: 2 hours 17 minutes, $99.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449396404_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Apache Cassandra is a robust second-generation distributed database. Its write-optimized shared-nothing architecture results in massive scalability, making it a popular choice at organizations such as Twitter, Digg, and Rackspace. This video covers the step-by-step setup of a single-node instance of Cassandra, before moving on to explore Twissandra, a simple Twitter clone written in Python and Django. Finally, best practices for provisioning and supporting a production cluster are presented.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449396404?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_apache_cassandra_in_action">
<title>Apache Cassandra in Action</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Jonathan Ellis</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, February 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449305789</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Running Time: 3 hours 4 minutes, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449305789_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Apache Cassandra is a second-generation distributed database originally open-sourced by Facebook. Its write-optimized shared-nothing architecture results in excellent performance and scalability. Follow along in this video that covers in-depth information on Cassandra presented by Jonathan Ellis, the cofounder of Cassandra.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/video/databases/business-intelligence/9781449305789?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">See it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_mongodb_the_definitive_guide">
<title>MongoDB: The Definitive Guide</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Kristina Chodorow; Michael Dirolf</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, September 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449381578</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>216 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449381578_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Discover how MongoDB can help you manage a huMONGOus amount of data collected through your web application. This book covers the basic principles and advanced uses of this document-oriented database, and demonstrates why MongoDB is scalable, high-performance, and reliable. This authoritative introduction, written by two software engineers from the company that develops this open-source database, offers guidance for programmers and advanced configuration for system administrators.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781449381578?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_50_tips_and_tricks_for_mongodb_developers">
<title>50 Tips and Tricks for MongoDB Developers</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Kristina Chodorow</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, April 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449306779</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>66 pages, $27.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449306779_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>This book is a collection of tips, tricks, and hacks to help MongoDB developers get the most out of the software. The tips cover everything from application design to data safety and monitoring.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781449306779?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_scaling_mongodb">
<title>Scaling MongoDB</title>
<simpara><emphasis>Kristina Chodorow</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, March 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449303679</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>60 pages, $29.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449303679_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Learn how to create large MongoDB clusters with this title! It shows how to use MongoDB efficiently for very large databases, covering sharding, cluster setup, and administration.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9781449303679?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
<chapter id="_visualization">
<title>Visualization</title>
<simpara>Data analysis and mining are difficult to use if they are not presented to users in a way they can understand.  This section
introduces visualization and a number of popular titles that show readers how to clearly express information.</simpara>
<sect1 id="_beautiful_visualization">
<title>Beautiful Visualization</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Julie Steele; Noah Iliinsky</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, June 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449379865</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>416 pages, $59.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449379889_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>With contributions from more than two dozen experts, this book demonstrates why visualizations are beautiful, not only for their aesthetic design, but also for elegant layers of detail that efficiently generate insight and new understanding. Think of the familiar map of the New York City subway system, or a diagram of the human brain. These older examples have been surpassed by artists, designers, commentators, scientists, analysts, statisticians, and others who show how visualizations using today’s digital capabilities can help us make sense of the world.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/software-engineering-and-development/9781449379889?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_visualize_this_the_flowingdata_guide_to_design_visualization_and_statistics">
<title>Visualize This: The FlowingData Guide to Design, Visualization, and Statistics</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Nathan Yau</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>John Wiley &amp; Sons, July 2011</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780470944882</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>384 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781118140260_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Data is ever-increasing and can be overwhelming to organize in a way that makes sense to its intended audience. Wouldn’t it be wonderful if we could actually visualize data to maximize its potential and tell a story in a clear, concise manner? Well, with this book you can. It explains how to gather, parse, and format data and then design high quality graphics that help you explore and present patterns, outliers, and relationships. Along the way you will be exposed to tools that visualize data-native graphics for the Web, such as ActionScript, Flash libraries, PHP, and JavaScript, along with tools to design graphics for print, such as R and Illustrator.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/web-development/usability/9781118140260?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_applied_security_visualization">
<title>Applied Security Visualization</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Raffael Marty</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>Addison-Wesley Professional, August, 2008</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780321510105</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>552 pages, $54.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780321585530_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>As networks become ever more complex, securing them becomes more and more difficult. The solution is visualization. Using today’s state-of-the-art data visualization techniques, you can gain a far deeper understanding of what’s happening on your network right now. You can uncover hidden patterns of data, identify emerging vulnerabilities and attacks, and respond decisively with countermeasures that are far more likely to succeed than conventional methods. In this book you will learn how to use visualization to perform broad network security analyses, assess specific threats, and even improve business compliance.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780321510105?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_visualizing_data">
<title>Visualizing Data</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Ben Fry</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, December, 2007</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596514556</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>384 pages, $39.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9780596514556_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Enormous quantities of data go unused or underused today, simply because people can’t visualize the quantities and relationships in it. This book demonstrates methods for representing data accurately on the Web and elsewhere, complete with user interaction, animation, and more. This book teaches you how to design entire interfaces around large, complex data sets with the help of a powerful new design and prototyping tool called “Processing,” which is used by many researchers and companies to convey specific data in a clear and understandable manner. With chapters divided by types of data rather than types of display, you’ll learn how each visualization conveys the unique properties of the data it represents — why the data was collected, what’s interesting about it, and what stories it can tell.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596514556?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_getting_started_with_processing">
<title>Getting Started with Processing</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Casey Reas; Ben Fry</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, June, 2010</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9781449379803</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>208 pages, $19.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/9781449379827_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Learn computer programming the easy way with Processing, a simple language that lets you use code to create drawings, animation, and interactive graphics. Programming courses usually start with theory, but this book lets you jump right into creative and fun projects. It’s ideal for anyone who wants to learn basic programming, and serves as a simple introduction to graphics for people with some programming skills.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/programming/processing/9781449379827?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="_information_dashboard_design">
<title>Information Dashboard Design</title>
<simpara><emphasis>By Stephen Few</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>O’Reilly Media, January, 2006</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>ISBN: 9780596100162</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara><emphasis>224 pages, $34.99 US</emphasis></simpara>
<informalfigure>
<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
  <imagedata fileref="images/0596100167_s.jpg" contentwidth="75"/>
  </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara>Dashboards have become popular in recent years as uniquely powerful tools for communicating important information at a glance. Although dashboards are potentially powerful, this potential is rarely realized. The greatest display technology in the world won’t solve this if you fail to use effective visual design. And if a dashboard fails to tell you precisely what you need to know in an instant, you’ll never use it, even if it’s filled with cute gauges, meters, and traffic lights. Don’t let your investment in dashboard technology go to waste. This book will teach you the visual design skills you need to create dashboards that communicate clearly, rapidly, and compellingly.</simpara>
<simpara><emphasis><ulink url="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/databases/business-intelligence/9780596100162?cid=1109-biblio-data-link">Read it on Safari Books Online</ulink></emphasis></simpara>
</sect1>
</chapter>
</book>
